<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjust Your Skill Queue</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a better sense of what you&amp;rsquo;re interested in doing in EVE,
it&amp;rsquo;s time to adjust your skill queue to train the skills that will help you
with your chosen activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few pages will walk through various aspects you might consider
for skill training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Adventure</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVE is a sandbox game, so there&amp;rsquo;s no particular progression for you to follow
once you&amp;rsquo;re past the tutorials. It&amp;rsquo;s time to figure out what you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the career agents&amp;rsquo; mission chains you should have a
little bit better sense of how some of the various EVE activities work. The
following pages will provide you with some more details about various options
for what you can do in EVE, and point you in the right direction for each of
them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join a Corporation</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/corps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/corps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While it is certainly possible to play EVE alone, it&amp;rsquo;s generally a lot more fun
to have a group of other people who share your interests. Joining a corporation
will give you many more options than you&amp;rsquo;d have flying alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;starter-npc-corps&#34;&gt;Starter NPC Corps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start the game in one of these, automatically assigned based on how you created
your character - your race and bloodline. If you ever join a different corp and then
quit it later, you&amp;rsquo;ll be placed back into another NPC corp based on your race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All NPC corps have a built-in tax rate of 10%. That means any mission rewards you earn
will be charged a 10% fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;factional-warfare-npc-corps&#34;&gt;Factional Warfare NPC Corps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faction Warfare (FW) allows you to sign up to PvP for your race&amp;rsquo;s empire in low-sec
space: Amarr vs. Minmatar and Caldari vs. Gallente. There are two ways of getting into
faction warfare - you can either join the empire&amp;rsquo;s FW NPC corp, or you can find a
player-run corp that participates in faction warfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details about Faction Warfare, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Factional Warfare&#34;&gt;UniWiki Factional Warfare guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;player-run-corps&#34;&gt;Player-run Corps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Players can create their own corporations (and in fact the majority of corporations
in EVE are player-created). These corporations can set their own tax rates, declare
war against one another, conquer parts of null-security space, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Learning</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/learn-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/learn-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this point you should be off to an excellent start in EVE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve explored different options for what to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have some ships with effective fits and know how to use them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have a plan for training new skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve (probably) found a group of people to play with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EVE has a lot of complexity. To explore more of it, consider checking out some of these other
excellent sites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org&#34;&gt;UniWiki&lt;/a&gt; is maintained by EVE University with articles on a wide
variety of EVE topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.braveineve.com/&#34;&gt;BRAVE Wiki&lt;/a&gt; is another wiki maintained by Brave Newbies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://crossingzebras.com/&#34;&gt;Crossing Zebras&lt;/a&gt; is an EVE fan site with many articles and podcasts about EVE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.eveonline.com/&#34;&gt;EVE Community&lt;/a&gt; site has news, patch notes, and forums to read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also browse the final section of this site (Reference Material) for individual tips and information that
didn&amp;rsquo;t fit into the &amp;ldquo;walkthrough&amp;rdquo; portion of the guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Material</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pages in this section don&amp;rsquo;t fit into the overall walkthrough in sections #1-9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse the list of references in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to Career Agents</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to the introductory tutorial, there are also a handful of Career Agents
which will provide you with various missions introducing you to a particular kind of
gameplay. These missions are an excellent way to explore some of the possibilities in
EVE while also acquiring some extra ISK and ship hulls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to a New Ship</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By this point you should have the resources to move on from the basic rookie ship to
something better. The ships you have available will depend on your race, so choose
the proper link below to go to the subsection appropriate for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/&#34;&gt;Amarr&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/caldari/&#34;&gt;Caldari&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/gallente/&#34;&gt;Gallente&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/minmatar/&#34;&gt;Minmatar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use the Market</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:35:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;searching-the-market&#34;&gt;Searching the Market&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When following this guide you&amp;rsquo;ll almost always be wanting particular items
from the market. The fastest way to find those items is use the search box.
Copy the name of the item and paste it into the box to the left of the
&amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; button, then click that button. A list of results (most likely
with only a single item, but sometimes more) will appear beneath.
Click the item in the result list to see where that item is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;buying-items&#34;&gt;Buying Items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When viewing market listings for a particular item you will see two sections:
Sellers and Buyers. We&amp;rsquo;re going to concentrate on the Sellers section for now
because we want to buy items from those Sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sort-your-sellers-list&#34;&gt;Sort your sellers list&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all: &lt;strong&gt;make sure your sellers are sorted by Price, ascending&lt;/strong&gt;.
This means that the price column should be the only column with an upwards-pointing
triangle on the right side of it. Try clicking the price column header to change the sorting.
Click the price column as many times as you need until it&amp;rsquo;s sorting properly. This is
to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not accidentally buying a highly overpriced version of the item
just because it happens to be a system closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorting by price also helps you avoid a scam where someone lists an item for what seems to
be a cheaper price, but actually has a few extra zeroes on the end - so you wind up
paying 1 million isk instead of 1 thousand isk or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;look-at-the-availability&#34;&gt;Look at the availability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look through the list. The first column, &lt;strong&gt;Jumps&lt;/strong&gt;, shows you how far you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go
to pick up the item after buying it. When you buy an item, you buy it in the station where
it was listed - not necessarily in your current station. So if the &amp;lsquo;Jumps&amp;rsquo; column reads
&amp;lsquo;5&amp;rsquo;, that means that after buying the item you&amp;rsquo;ll need to jump through 5 stargates to reach
the system where you bought the item. If the jumps column says &amp;lsquo;System&amp;rsquo; it means the item
is located in your current system but a different station, and if it says &amp;lsquo;Station&amp;rsquo; it means
that it&amp;rsquo;s listed in the same station you&amp;rsquo;re currently in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;strong&gt;Quantity&lt;/strong&gt; - displaying how many items are available via that seller. If you want
to buy more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get them from multiple sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Price&lt;/strong&gt; column lists the price per unit being offered; if the listed price is 100.00
ISK and you want to buy 50 of the item, you&amp;rsquo;ll wind up paying 5000 ISK total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see exactly which station the items are listed from in the &lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; column. This is
important - before buying items in another system, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to check to make sure
you can get there without having to go through low-security space (0.4 and below). Otherwise
you might get ganked on the way. You can right-click on a particular seller and choose
Location -&amp;gt; Set Destination to a set an autopilot course to it, and then look at the colored
dots that the autopilot shows you: if any of them are orange or red, don&amp;rsquo;t buy from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit Your Rookie Ship</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 17:26:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;re done with the tutorial (and probably just got your ship blown up),
you might be wondering what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t panic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest ship to get your hands on is your own race&amp;rsquo;s corvette (typically known
as a &amp;ldquo;rookie ship&amp;rdquo;). You get one for free if you don&amp;rsquo;t have any other ships in the
station you&amp;rsquo;re in. In fact, you probably already have one if you docked up after
exploding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can significantly improve the effectiveness of your rookie ship by properly fitting
it with modules bought from the market. Select your race below to see a suggested fit
for your racial rookie ship that you can use without having to train more skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/amarr/&#34;&gt;Amarr&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/caldari/&#34;&gt;Caldari&lt;/a&gt; /
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/gallente/&#34;&gt;Gallente&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/rookie-fitting/minmatar/&#34;&gt;Minmatar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 16:35:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/start/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;span-style-color-e00-font-weight-bold-font-size-300-text-shadow-2px-2px-a00-line-height-100-don-t-panic-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e00;font-weight:bold;font-size:300%;text-shadow:2px 2px #a00;line-height:100%;&#34;&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T PANIC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-alpha-s-guide-to-the-galaxy&#34;&gt;The Alpha&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guide for alpha-clone players of EVE Online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Agent</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:59:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/business/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This mission chain is &lt;strong&gt;Balancing the Books&lt;/strong&gt;. Its 10 missions will have you doing
salvaging, hacking, mining, and a bit of running around delivering things to agents
in different systems. These are ways that you can make money in EVE without having
to use your weapons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get stuck, there&amp;rsquo;s a video guide to the missions that begins
here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2RtjAYs8spU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2RtjAYs8spU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the video guide was made in 2015, the older interfaces may look a bit
different from what you see now, but the general steps to complete the mission
will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you complete the chain, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a couple of new ships, some skill books,
some modules, and a good chunk of ISK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;common-stumbling-blocks&#34;&gt;Common Stumbling Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 2 of 10, the Black Box will be ejected into a Cargo Container
when you destroy the last pirate.  Remember to pick it up before returning to station.
If you forgot, you can warp back to the mission site within 2 hours and it will still be there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 3 of 10, the Veldspar must be mined in the mission site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 6 of 10, the Tracking Computer I is most easily acquired from the Market.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/&#34;&gt;Use the Market&lt;/a&gt; section if you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 9 of 10, you can use &lt;code&gt;1MN Afterburner I&lt;/code&gt; modules acquired from other Career Agent
missions or from the Market.  Make sure they are Repackaged (right-click -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Repackage&amp;rdquo;)
or the agent will not accept them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 10 of 10, the manufacturing process will take substantial time;
you can do other things (such as other career agent missions) while the build is in progress.
Some of the minerals required may be most easily sourced through the Market rather than via mining.
You can also just buy the ammunition off the market, despite what the agent says.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration Agent</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:59:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/exploration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This mission chain walks you through how to use the scanning interfaces
in EVE. Scanning lets you locate things like wormholes, data and relic sites
to hack, and even other players&amp;rsquo; ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scanning interfaces can be a little hard to understand without seeing
them in operation. Thankfully, EVE has a set of built-in video tutorials
for how to use the scanning interfaces. To view them, press F12 to open
the &amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; window, then select the &amp;ldquo;Tutorial Videos&amp;rdquo; tab. Scroll down to
the &amp;ldquo;Exploration&amp;rdquo; subsection (click to expand it). Then watch the following
videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scanning (1 of 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scanning (2 of 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacking Data and Relic sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other videos are also interesting, but aren&amp;rsquo;t relevant to this particular
mission chain - feel free to watch them when you have the time and interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you complete the chain, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a couple of new ships (including one
specifically designed for exploration), some skill books, some modules,
and a good chunk of ISK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;common-stumbling-blocks&#34;&gt;Common Stumbling Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On mission 3 of 5, you&amp;rsquo;ll be required to find a &amp;ldquo;Data Site&amp;rdquo;.
This is a Cosmic Signature, and you will not be able to warp to it without using scanner probes.
Review the Scanning (2 or 3) video to learn how to use these probes to find the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On mission 5 of 5, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a Passkey with you to be able to enter the final site.
It&amp;rsquo;s provided to you when you begin the mission; remember to put it in your cargohold before you undock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Agent</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/industry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:59:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/industry/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This chain is &lt;strong&gt;Making Mountains of Molehills&lt;/strong&gt;. Its 10 missions focus
on how to produce new items in EVE from scratch: mining raw materials
and then building modules, charges (ammo), and ships from those materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble figuring out how to use the industry interface,
you can watch the tutorial videos provided in-game. Press F12 to open the
&amp;ldquo;Help&amp;rdquo; window, then click the &amp;ldquo;Tutorial Videos&amp;rdquo; tab. Scroll down to the
&amp;ldquo;Industry&amp;rdquo; section and watch the &amp;ldquo;Manufacturing&amp;rdquo; video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you complete the chain, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a couple of new ships, some skill
books, some modules, and a good chunk of isk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;common-stumbling-blocks&#34;&gt;Common Stumbling Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 2 of 10, note that the Veldspar must be in the station&amp;rsquo;s Item Hangar,
not your ship&amp;rsquo;s Cargo Hold, before it can be Reprocessed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 3 of 10, the &lt;code&gt;1MN Civilian Afterburner I Blueprint&lt;/code&gt; must be purchased from the Market.
It should cost 20,000 ISK.  See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/&#34;&gt;Use the Market&lt;/a&gt; section if you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 4 of 10, note that ore must be mined from the mission site to complete all mission objectives.
Using ore mined from other asteroid belts, or previous mission steps, won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to finish it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 9 of 10, make sure that you have both a mining laser and a weapon fit to your ship.
Having only one or the other will be insufficient to complete the mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 10 of 10, the minerals you will need come from a variety of different ores.
See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Asteroids_and_Ore#Asteroid_distribution&#34;&gt;EVE University page on Asteroids and Ore&lt;/a&gt; for the locations of the appropriate ores.  Note that Zydrine cannot be obtained from high-security asteroids, except in randomly-spawning Ore anomalies.  It may be quickest and easiest to simply buy the rarer minerals from the Market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Military Agents</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/military/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:59:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/career-agents/military/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There are actually two military career agents - the regular Military Agent and the Advanced Military Agent.
We recommend doing both chains - first the regular agent, then the advanced agent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;military-agent&#34;&gt;Military Agent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regular Military Agent focuses on teaching you the basics of PvE combat missions
in the chain &lt;strong&gt;Cash Flow for Capsuleers&lt;/strong&gt;. Missions like these are one of the main
ways for making ISK in EVE via PvE combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get stuck along the way, there&amp;rsquo;s a video guide to the missions that begins here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ic8U2sX7yd4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ic8U2sX7yd4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the video guide was made in 2014, the older interfaces may look a bit different
from what you see now, but the general steps to complete the mission will be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you complete this chain, you&amp;rsquo;ll earn a couple of new ships, some skill books, some
modules, and a good chunk of isk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;common-stumbling-blocks&#34;&gt;Common Stumbling Blocks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 3 of 10, the Secret Documents will appear in a Cargo Container after you
kill the last pirate.  Make sure to loot them before you dock.  If you forgot them,
you can return to the Mission location for up to two hours afterwards, and they will still be there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 4 of 10, pay attention to your Local chat channel to see when you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 5 of 10, you need to destroy the pirate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In mission 9 of 10, the Narcotics Warehouse may not appear on your overview.
It is one of the man-made structures around the large asteroid.
Search for it visually, and destroy it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;advanced-military-agent&#34;&gt;Advanced Military Agent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Advanced Military Agent focuses on teaching you some of the concepts typically
involved in PvP combat (though the agent&amp;rsquo;s missions do not actually involve PvP).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amarr Ships</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of your Career Agent missions,
they will have given you some of the following ships.
They are more powerful than your rookie ship.
They are also more specialized, and each ship is built for a specific purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;frigates&#34;&gt;Frigates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frigates are some of the fastest and smallest ships in New Eden.
This makes them very difficult for larger ships to hit.
Their guns also track very quickly, allowing them to effectively fight other frigates.
However, their raw defensive and offensive power is relatively weak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;executioner&#34;&gt;Executioner&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Executioner is the Amarr fast-attack frigate.
It is extremely quick, and packs a decent punch.
Its bonus to the capacitor cost of Propulsion Jamming modules
also makes it good at &amp;ldquo;tackling&amp;rdquo; enemy ships, holding them in place.
However, it is relatively fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/executioner/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Executioner.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;tormentor&#34;&gt;Tormentor&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tormentor is the Amarr heavy attack frigate.
It gets substantial bonuses to its three energy turrets,
and is otherwise well-rounded, with decent defenses,
sufficient midslots to offer some utility, and a moderate drone bay.
However, it is somewhat slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/tormentor/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Tormentor.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;punisher&#34;&gt;Punisher&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Punisher is the Amarr heavy combat frigate.
It is incredibly durable, and has potent firepower.
However, it is quite slow, and its limited midslots limit its utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/punisher/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Punisher.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;magnate&#34;&gt;Magnate&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Magnate is the Amarr exploration frigate.
It has substantial bonuses to the use of scanner probes and relic/data analyzers,
making it a powerful option for exploration-minded capsuleers.
However, it is fragile, and weak in direct combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/magnate/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Magnate.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;inquisitor&#34;&gt;Inquisitor&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Inquisitor is the Amarr logistics frigate.
It has potent bonuses to remote armor repair modules,
allowing it to &amp;ldquo;heal&amp;rdquo; allied ships in battle.
However, it is not very useful to a solo pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, we recommend that you do not use the Inquisitor for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;crucifier&#34;&gt;Crucifier&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Crucifier is the Amarr electronic warfare frigate.
It has powerful bonuses to the effectiveness of weapon disruptor modules,
allowing it to degrade its enemies&amp;rsquo; range and accuracy while staying safely out of range itself.
However, it is extremely fragile, and is not very useful to a solo pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, we recommend that you do not use the Crucifier for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;venture&#34;&gt;Venture&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Venture is a mining frigate, not specific to any one empire.
It has powerful bonuses to its mining lasers and gas harvesters,
as well as a vast ore hold, allowing it to accumulate massive amounts of raw resources.
It also has innate resistance to warp disruption, allowing it to escape attackers more easily.
However, it is not particularly suitable for combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/venture/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Venture.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;destroyers&#34;&gt;Destroyers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Destroyers are designed as a counter to frigates.
They are &amp;ldquo;glass cannons&amp;rdquo; - they get large numbers of frigate-class guns,
with substantial enhancements to their range and tracking,
making them able to swat frigates out of the sky with ease.
However,  their defenses are little stronger than a frigate&amp;rsquo;s,
and their larger size and slower speed makes them less able to avoid the fire
of larger ships.  They are also lacking in any utility besides their damage output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;coercer&#34;&gt;Coercer&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Coercer is one of the Amarr destroyers, focusing on laser turrets.
With the maximum of eight hardpoints for energy weapons,
and with potent bonuses to their range and accuracy,
it will quickly destroy any smaller enemies that come near it.
However, it is very slow compared to frigates, and its size makes it much easier to hit.
Additionally, it has very little utility outside of its lasers&amp;rsquo; damage output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/coercer/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Coercer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;dragoon&#34;&gt;Dragoon&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dragoon is the other Amarr destroyer, focusing on drones and energy neutralization.
It has only three hardpoints for each of turrets and launchers,
but can field a full flight of five light drones and two more flights in reserve,
with bonuses to their damage and speed.
It also gains bonuses to the range of Energy Neutralizers, used to directly attack
enemies&amp;rsquo; capacitors in PvP.
Its drones give it long reach, but its maximum damage output is low
and its neutralizer bonuses are not useful in PvE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/dragoon/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Dragoon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cruisers&#34;&gt;Cruisers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cruisers, as a class, are the most well-rounded ships in New Eden.  With comfortable slot layouts,
decent firepower, good defenses, moderate speed, and moderate price,
they&amp;rsquo;re the standard by which other ships are measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cruiser fittings will not be provided in this guide.  By the time you&amp;rsquo;re getting
into a cruiser, you should be creating fits for yourself; see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/fitting/&#34;&gt;Fitting&lt;/a&gt; if you need some pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;battlecruisers&#34;&gt;Battlecruisers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battlecruisers are to cruisers as destroyers are to frigates:
much more heavily armed, but substantially slower.  Battlecruisers are
also significantly better defended, yet also more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gnosis is the only battlecruiser available to Alpha clones.
It is available to all races, and offers moderate bonuses to
nearly all weapons systems and defenses while excelling in none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Gnosis fitting will not be provided in this guide. By the time you&amp;rsquo;re getting
into a battlecruiser, you should be creating fits for yourself; see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/fitting/&#34;&gt;Fitting&lt;/a&gt; if you need some pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;industrials&#34;&gt;Industrials&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industrials, as class, are non-combat ships focused on the transport of goods across New Eden.
They have massive cargo holds, but are slow, clumsy, and poorly armed at best - if they&amp;rsquo;re armed at all.
They can be a great boon to a marketeer, industrialist,
or even a combat pilot restocking on gear or moving locations,
but are borderline useless in combat and a favorite target of player pirates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;sigil&#34;&gt;Sigil&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sigil is one of the Amarr industrials.
It has a massive cargo hold, and can mount sufficient defenses to stave off light attacks
long enough for reinforcements to arrive.
However, it is extremely slow and clumsy, and is borderline useless in combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/amarr/sigil/&#34;&gt;Here is a recommended fit for the Sigil.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>