<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reference-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Material</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pages in this section don&amp;rsquo;t fit into the overall walkthrough in sections #1-9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse the list of references in the menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fit Ships Well</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/fitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/fitting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The walkthrough portion of this guide has a number of suggested fits, but perhaps
you want to design your own fits - or a fit for a ship that isn&amp;rsquo;t mentioned.
Well, as they say&amp;hellip;give a capsuleer a fit and they&amp;rsquo;ll fly for a day.
Teach a capsuleer to fit, and they&amp;rsquo;ll keep flying for the rest of their immortal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is intended to teach you how to do just that,
outlining some of the theory and practice of creating your own ship fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an alternate resource written for Omega clones, you can look at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Fitting_Guidelines&#34;&gt;EVE University Fitting Guide&lt;/a&gt;
for another perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-ll-do-it-live&#34;&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll Do It Live!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Don&amp;rsquo;t do it live.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could make a fit by simply buying modules off the market,
then throwing together whatever you have room for.  This will result in a lot
of wasted money, though, especially when you start messing with Rigs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s better to simulate the fit ahead of time.
There&amp;rsquo;s a Simulation Mode built right into the game to help you plan out your fits.
If you open your fitting window (with alt+F), then at the top-right, there will
be a white ship silhouette.  Clicking on that will let you enter &amp;ldquo;Simulation Mode&amp;rdquo;,
constructing a fit from any modules in the game, using your own skills at the time,
without having to buy a thing.  You&amp;rsquo;ll want to expand the Browser (the wrench on the left)
and the Attributes (the tab on the right) while building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternately, there&amp;rsquo;s several out-of-game tools to do this, the most notable being
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pyfa-org/pyfa/releases/&#34;&gt;Python Fitting Assistant (Pyfa)&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://o.smium.org/&#34;&gt;Osmium&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.eveonline.com/default.aspx?g=posts&amp;amp;t=24359&#34;&gt;EVE Fitting Tool (EFT)&lt;/a&gt;,
though EFT is no longer being updated and is now several months out of date.
Some of these have additional features, such as seeing how the fit would
vary with different skill levels or testing its damage application
against a variety of targets, or they can just be used
while you&amp;rsquo;re away from the game client itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When fitting your ship, there&amp;rsquo;s a few different constraints that limit what you can use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Power Grid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Slot Layout.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ship&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Turret and Launcher Hardpoints.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re also limited by your skills in what you can fit,
and the effectiveness of the modules you do fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These resources are limits: you can&amp;rsquo;t fit modules that would take you over your
maximum CPU or Power Grid, and you can&amp;rsquo;t fit modules to slots you don&amp;rsquo;t have.
There&amp;rsquo;s no benefit to &amp;ldquo;saving&amp;rdquo; them, though;
a ship with 100 spare CPU doesn&amp;rsquo;t get any benefit over a ship with
0.0 spare CPU, but a ship with -0.1 CPU left will have to offline some of its modules
until it&amp;rsquo;s back under the limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the art of fitting, therefore, lies in spending these resources most efficiently.
If you have spare CPU/Grid/Slots, you should be asking yourself
&amp;ldquo;Is there a way I could use more of them to improve this fit&amp;rdquo;?
When you&amp;rsquo;re using up a slot by fitting a module, ask yourself
&amp;ldquo;How does this module contribute to the goal of the fit?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;specialization&#34;&gt;Specialization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In EVE, your ship is not your character; your ship is a tool.
Each tool has its own specified purpose.  You might be able to use a wrench
to hammer in nails, or a screwdriver to drill a hole, but it&amp;rsquo;s far better
to use the tool built to do those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, it&amp;rsquo;s usually better to fit a ship to be very good at one thing,
rather than mediocre at a lot of things.  Then, when flying,
concentrate on keeping yourself in your optimal situation whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, it&amp;rsquo;s better to build a ship with a lot of the same type of guns
in order to be excellent at fighting at a range of about 10km,
rather than fitting a smattering of different weapons to do
poor damage anywhere from 1km to 20km.
A lot of what you&amp;rsquo;ll be doing when piloting that ship, then,
is doing whatever you can to ensure that you and your foes stay separated by about 10km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When coming up with a focus for the fit, a good first stop is to check the ship&amp;rsquo;s bonuses,
in the &amp;ldquo;Traits&amp;rdquo; tab of its &amp;ldquo;Show Info&amp;rdquo; window.
A ship bonused for armor repairs and hybrid turrets should probably be
an active-tanked armor fit with blasters, not a shield-buffer droneboat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One aspect of &amp;ldquo;specialization&amp;rdquo; is that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;dual-tank&amp;rdquo;.
That is, don&amp;rsquo;t fit both shield and armor modules to the same ship;
focus your resources on having a strong armor tank &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; a strong shield tank.
Modules for one don&amp;rsquo;t help the other, and if you can&amp;rsquo;t survive in one &amp;ldquo;layer&amp;rdquo;,
it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that the other will do much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;slots&#34;&gt;Slots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, by now you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that your ship has High, Medium, Low, and Rig slots.
It might seem a little random what goes where, though.
What separates a High slot from a Low slot, or a Medium from a Rig?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every piece of equipment can be fit to exactly one of these slot types.
Each type of slot, therefore, has a set of things that you can use that slot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to browse what your options are, in the &amp;ldquo;Hardware&amp;rdquo; tab of the simulator,
you can set the filters to only show modules for a given slot type,
and modules that fit only with your skills and the remaining fitting resources on your ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following sections will outline some of the main things you can use each slot type on.
The list is not exhaustive, but covers the majority of options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;high-slots&#34;&gt;High Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High slots primarily bear offensive armament - most notably,
your ship&amp;rsquo;s weapons, whether Turrets or Launchers.
It&amp;rsquo;s almost always best to fit as many Turrets/Launchers as you have hardpoints
(one or the other, if your ship has both), as that&amp;rsquo;s where most of your damage will come from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have leftover high slots after using up all Hardpoints,
then you can fit what&amp;rsquo;s known as a &amp;ldquo;utility high&amp;rdquo;, modules that
provide some kind of benefit other than direct damage output to your locked target.
These can be things like Energy Neutralizers that drain your enemy&amp;rsquo;s capacitor,
Smartbombs to deal a pulse of area damage around yourself (good for clearing drones),
Salvagers to pick the bones of wrecks, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, high slots hold certain specialized equipment
for less combat-oriented ships.  Probe Launchers for scanning ships,
Remote Armor Repairers and Remote Shield Boosters to &amp;ldquo;heal&amp;rdquo; your allies for logistics ships,
Tractor Beams for industrials gathering cargo ejected by allied ships,
and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;mid-slots&#34;&gt;Mid Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid slots tend to contain CPU-intensive systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One module that nearly every ship will want is a Propulsion Module
of choice - either an Afterburner or a Microwarpdrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mids are also used for Shield modules, meaning that they&amp;rsquo;re the
primary &amp;ldquo;defensive&amp;rdquo; slots of most Caldari and Minmatar ships.
Shield Boosters will restore your shields in exchange for large amounts of capacitor,
while Shield Extenders provide a passive boost to your maximum HP
(but make your ship slightly easier to hit).
Whichever you choose, they&amp;rsquo;re well complemented by Shield Hardeners,
which increase your shields&amp;rsquo; resistance to damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mids are also used for Electronic Warfare modules, such as
stasis webifiers, ECM, sensor dampeners, weapon disruptors, and target painters.
Notably for PvP fits, this is where you&amp;rsquo;ll find Warp Disruptors and Warp Scramblers,
&amp;ldquo;tackle&amp;rdquo; modules that prevent your target from simply warping away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also some capacitor-enhancing modules: Capacitor Batteries,
which increase your maximum capacitor; Capacitor Rechargers,
which passively increase your recharge rate; and Capacitor Boosters,
which let you use Cap Booster charges as &amp;ldquo;ammo&amp;rdquo; for instant injections of energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there&amp;rsquo;s various modules that let you enhance some aspects of your own
or other ships, usually in exchange for a small amount of capacitor.
Tracking Computers, Sensor Boosters, Missile Guidance Computers,
and Omnidirectional Tracking Links, among others, fall under this heading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;low-slots&#34;&gt;Low Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low slots tend to contain passive modules and/or Power Grid-intensive systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One module that nearly every ship will want is a &amp;ldquo;Damage Control&amp;rdquo;,
which provides a mild boost to your shield and armor resistances,
but a huge bonus to the toughness of your hull.  A Damage Control
is one of the most efficient ways to gain EHP (Effective Hit Points),
and will give you more time to try and warp out - or kill your attacker -
if things are going badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lows are also used for Armor modules, meaning that they&amp;rsquo;re the primary
&amp;ldquo;defensive&amp;rdquo; slots of most Amarr and Gallente ships.
Armor Repairers will restore your armor over time in exchange for capacitor,
while Armor Plates provide a passive boost to your maximum HP (but slow down your ship).
Whichever you choose, they&amp;rsquo;re well complemented by Armor Hardeners,
which increase your armor&amp;rsquo;s resistance to damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other main use is Damage Mods: passive modules that improve your
weapons&amp;rsquo; damage and rate of fire.  There&amp;rsquo;s a different type for each weapon system:
Gyrostabilizers for projectiles, Magnetic Field Stabilizers for hybrids,
Heat Sinks for lasers, Ballistic Control Systems for missiles,
and Drone Damage Amplifiers for drones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, lowslots can contain modules that give your ship more fitting room.
Auxiliary Power Cores, Reactor Control Units, and Power Diagnostic Systems
will give your ship more Power Grid, while Co-Processors will give it more CPU.
Try not to spend too many slots on these; usually if you have to spend more
than one or two slots on &amp;ldquo;fitting mods&amp;rdquo;, you should be scaling things back elsewhere instead.
Slots are a resource, spend them wisely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;rigs&#34;&gt;Rigs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rigs are passive modifications to your ship,
which generally trade off one attribute for another.
Unlike modules, they cannot be removed, only destroyed or replaced with another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rigs have a &amp;ldquo;calibration cost&amp;rdquo;, which is sort of like CPU or Power Grid but applies only to rigs.
You can&amp;rsquo;t fit rigs that exceed your ship&amp;rsquo;s maximum Calibration (usually 400, with rigs
usually costing between 50 and 200 apiece).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which rig is appropriate to your ship is going to depend highly on what you want your fit to do.
Some common ones, though this is by no means an exhaustive list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shield/Armor Resistance Rigs (Anti-[TYPE] Screen Reinforcer or Anti-[TYPE] Pump)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shield/Armor HP Rigs (Core Defense Field Extender or Trimark Armor Pump)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacitor Rigs (Capacitor Control Circuit or Semiconductor Memory Cell)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitting Rigs (Ancillary Current Router or Processor Overclocking Unit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weapon Rigs ([TYPE] Collision Accelerator or [TYPE] Burst Aerator)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;drones&#34;&gt;Drones&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ship&amp;rsquo;s Drone Bay can be considered part of its weapon system;
usually the best Drone Bays are found on Gallente and Amarr ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which Drones you can use depends on the ship&amp;rsquo;s Drone Capacity and its Drone Bandwidth.
You can see these in the &amp;ldquo;Attributes&amp;rdquo; tab of the ship&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Show Info&amp;rdquo; window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light Drones take 5 m3 of space to store and 5 Mbit/sec of bandwidth to control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium Drones take 10 m3 of space to store and 10 Mbit/sec of bandwidth to control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heavy Drones take 25 m3 of space to store and 25 Mbit/sec of bandwidth to control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your pilot can control no more than five drones at any one time, and two &amp;ldquo;smaller&amp;rdquo;
drones is almost always better than one &amp;ldquo;bigger&amp;rdquo; drone.
So, a ship with 25 Mbit/sec bandwidth and 40 m3 bay, like the Tristan,
can control a &amp;ldquo;full flight&amp;rdquo; of five light drones with three in reserve;
the Algos, with 35 Mbit/sec and 60 m3, would be better served by a
primary flight of 2x Medium and 3x Light, with 5x Light in reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with weapons and ships, bigger isn&amp;rsquo;t always better when it comes to drones; see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;module-size&#34;&gt;Module Size&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably been using primarily frigates and destroyers, which use &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; modules.
Cruisers and Battlecruisers use &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; modules, and Battleships use &amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo;.
Module sizing is primarily applied to weaponry, defensive modules, and propulsion modules.
Capacitor Batteries and Capacitor Injectors also have size variations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary difference is that larger modules have more raw power,
but take massively increased amounts of powergrid to fit.
In the case of weapons, they&amp;rsquo;ll also have difficulty tracking smaller, nimbler targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a frigate&amp;rsquo;s 400mm Steel Plates give 900 armor HP,
but add 350k kg to its mass (making it slower and more sluggish to handle)
and costing 20 CPU and 30 grid.  By contrast, a battleship&amp;rsquo;s 1600mm Steel Plates
give 3500 HP, but add 3.5 million kg to its mass and cost 30 tf and 500 grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or for weapons, a full rack of 280mm Howitzer Artillery on a Thrasher-class destroyer
will deal approximately 2000 damage a volley, and cost about 70 grid to fit,
with a &amp;ldquo;tracking score&amp;rdquo; (how well it tracks moving targets;
see &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Gunnery_Guide#Tracking&#34;&gt;the UniWiki Gunnery Guide&lt;/a&gt;) of about 100.
A rack of 1400mm Howitzer Artillery on a Maelstrom-class battleship
will deal about 10000 damage per volley, but will cost about 20,000 grid to fit
and track a hundred times more slowly - it&amp;rsquo;ll have a hard time hitting anything but other battleships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, frigates&amp;rsquo; small size and high speed lets them evade shots from heavier ships
with relative ease.  If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about moving up into a cruiser,
keep this in mind: you should definitely use Medium guns for their better
range and damage output, but Light drones may be of assistance
in dispatching the pesky frigates that your guns will have difficulty tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;module-caliber&#34;&gt;Module Caliber&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within size classes, there can be smaller variations.
Most notably, most guns come in different &amp;ldquo;calibers&amp;rdquo; -
for example, projectile Autocannons come in 125mm, 150mm, and 200mm variants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A larger-caliber gun deals more damage-per-second, has a longer range,
and has a slower refire rate (meaning it can have greatly increased &amp;ldquo;alpha-strike&amp;rdquo; damage per shot).
In exchange, it has poorer tracking, making it less useful against fast, small, close-in targets,
and has higher fitting costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is most common to try and fit the largest caliber you can initially, for maximum damage,
and then downsize the guns if you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough CPU or powergrid.
There are some exceptions for dedicated anti-small-ship setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;caliber&amp;rdquo; model somewhat holds for defensive modules, as well;
for example, a frigate can mount a 100mm, 200mm or 400mm armor plate, with more severe
fitting costs and speed reductions as the size increases.
It&amp;rsquo;s almost always best to fit the largest module you can get away with,
as this makes the most efficient use of the slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have sufficient fitting resources, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to prevent you
from fitting an &amp;ldquo;oversized&amp;rdquo; defensive module, intended for larger size classes,
such as a battleship&amp;rsquo;s 1600mm Steel Plate mounted on a cruiser.
This places severe strain on its powergrid, but grants excellent protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is almost always a bad idea for weapons, however; your ship will not have bonuses for their use,
they probably won&amp;rsquo;t be suitable to their fighting style/fighting other ships of similar size,
your ship may not have the capacitor to maintain fire (for Hybrids and Lasers),
and it&amp;rsquo;s doubtful you&amp;rsquo;d have the fitting space to mount a full rack in any event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stacking-penalties&#34;&gt;Stacking Penalties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be tempting to simply cram every low slot full of damage mods,
with visions of rat-bounty ISK dancing in your head.
However, fitting multiple modules that do the same thing will gradually decrease in effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tell if a module&amp;rsquo;s subject to stacking penalties by looking for the phrase
&amp;ldquo;Using more than one type of this module or similar modules that affect the same
attribute on the ship will be penalized.&amp;rdquo; in the Description tab of their Show Info window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two modules of the same type is usually fine, as the 2nd mod is about 87% effective -
and for modules that add a multiplicative bonus to the stat in question,
the second can actually wind up more effective than the first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third will only be 57% effective, so it may be better to begin looking elsewhere
for an alternate way to use that slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth will be 28% effective; it&amp;rsquo;s almost always better to find something else
to use the slot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fifth is 10% effective, and the 6th 3% effective.  There is basically never
a reason to fit a module that would be seeing fifth or sixth stacking penalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacking penalties apply to all bonuses to the same stat.  For example, if you
have an &amp;ldquo;EM Ward Field&amp;rdquo; shield hardener boosting your shield&amp;rsquo;s EM resists,
and an &amp;ldquo;Anti-EM Screen Reinforcer&amp;rdquo; rig also boosting your shield&amp;rsquo;s EM resists,
the rig would face stacking penalties.  However, if it was instead an
&amp;ldquo;Anti-Thermal Screen Reinforcer&amp;rdquo; rig to boost your Thermal resists,
they would be improving different stats and would not be penalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stacking penalties apply in the most favorable order to you:
the most powerful bonus applies at full strength,
the next-best at second stacking penalty, and so on.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about the order you fit things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resistance-is-futile&#34;&gt;Resistance Is Futile&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ship&amp;rsquo;s resistances are a critical part of its defenses.
Having higher resists lets your HP last longer,
making shield boosting/armor repair more effective
and multiplying the impact of shield extenders/armor plates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two main strategies for how to improve your resists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;omni-resists&#34;&gt;Omni Resists&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most common strategy, especially for PvP fits.
It involves trying to make sure all of your resists
in your primary tanking layer (shield or armor) are roughly even,
so that you have no &amp;ldquo;resist holes&amp;rdquo; an enemy can exploit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For shields, this usually means shoring up EM and Thermal.
For armor, this usually means boosting Explosive and possibly Kinetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve equalized your resists, you should start applying omni-resist modules,
such as Adaptive Nano Platings and Adaptive Invulnerability Fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;resist-stacking&#34;&gt;Resist Stacking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is less common, but seen moderately often in PvE fits,
and occasionally seen in niche PvP fits.
If you know the damage type your opponent is going to be using,
you can simply focus all your resistances in that category.
This leaves your ship with glaring &amp;ldquo;resist holes&amp;rdquo; against other damage types,
but so long as nobody shoots you in those, it can make you much stronger against your preferred foe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your primary tool for resist stacking will be damage-type-specific
Shield Hardeners and Armor Hardeners, and possibly resistance rigs.
Be wary of stacking penalties, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that canny gankers are well aware of the practice of resist stacking for missions,
and may specifically load their weapons with a damage type not dealt by the local rats.
If you&amp;rsquo;re ratting in dangerous space, or doing missions in an expensive ship
that may attract unsavory attention, be forewarned of the dangers of leaving a resist hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;meta-is-betta&#34;&gt;Meta Is Betta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;ldquo;improved&amp;rdquo; fits from earlier, you may have noticed some modules with somewhat odd names,
relative to the relatively simple ones from the starter fits.
&amp;ldquo;Sure, I know what a Light Neutron Blaster is, but what in the world
is a &lt;code&gt;Modal Light Neutron Particle Accelerator I&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most modules have what are known as &amp;ldquo;meta&amp;rdquo; versions,
which grant improved effectiveness at lower fitting costs.
Meta modules can&amp;rsquo;t be built directly, and are instead looted from rats;
this means their prices can vary widely, as supply and demand aren&amp;rsquo;t directly linked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see the meta versions of a module, check its &amp;ldquo;Variations&amp;rdquo; tab.
You can also directly compare stats of the variations with the &amp;ldquo;Compare&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two types of common variations: the &amp;ldquo;meta 1-4&amp;rdquo; style, and the &amp;ldquo;specializations&amp;rdquo; style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;meta-1-4&#34;&gt;Meta 1-4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some modules, such as guns, simply have four alternate versions with
gradually increasing effectiveness.  If you look in the &amp;ldquo;Attributes&amp;rdquo; tab,
the &amp;ldquo;Meta Level&amp;rdquo; lets you know which it is - they&amp;rsquo;re also listed in increasing order
in the Variations tab (the last one is the meta4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each meta level grants about a 5% increase to some aspect of the module.
A meta 4 module is about 20% more effective than the baseline version.
They also come with reductions in fitting cost,
though the exact amounts vary from module to module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta 4 modules tend to be much more expensive than the others.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on a budget, a meta 3 or meta 2 module can often be had for
dirt cheap - even cheaper than the baseline, meta 0 item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;specializations&#34;&gt;Specializations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new model, which CCP&amp;rsquo;s gradually converting existing modules to,
is a more specialization-based concept - rather than &amp;ldquo;meta 4 is the best&amp;rdquo;,
each variation has its own specific attribute it focuses on improving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modules which follow this pattern have a consistent naming convention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Compact&amp;rdquo; modules have reduced fitting costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enduring&amp;rdquo; modules have more efficient capacitor usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Restrained&amp;rdquo; modules have lower penalties (such as the speed reduction from armor plates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ample&amp;rdquo; modules have a larger charge (ammo) capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Scoped&amp;rdquo; modules have a longer range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Upgraded&amp;rdquo; modules have moderately better stats all around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will often still be improvements over the base, meta 0 version even in aspects
that don&amp;rsquo;t match their specialty; for example, a Restrained Shield Extender
gives more HP than a baseline Shield Extender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;beyond-meta&#34;&gt;Beyond Meta&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the tech one &amp;ldquo;meta&amp;rdquo; modules, there&amp;rsquo;s other improvements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech II modules (yellow), produced by industrialists,
with higher fitting costs and larger penalties,
but 20-50% stronger than baseline versions and about 10x as expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faction modules (green), looted from rare &amp;ldquo;faction spawn&amp;rdquo; rats,
with substantially easier fitting and better effectiveness than Tech II modules,
but about 10x as expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadspace modules (blue), looted from Cosmic Anomaly and Cosmic Signature Combat sites
(&amp;ldquo;dungeons&amp;rdquo; which require powerful and specialized ships to clear), tougher to fit than
Faction modules but substantially more effective, and about 10x as expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officer modules (purple), looted from extremely rare Officer spawns in deep null-security space,
the toughest to fit but the most effective, about 10x as expensive as Deadspace modules.
Rarely fit to anything short of supercapital vessels due to their sheer expense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech II modules are the &amp;ldquo;gold standard&amp;rdquo;, which most pilots will try to fit as a default.
Meta modules let pilots ease up on fitting, while faction and deadspace modules
allow improvements to a specific aspect of a ship - though at a great cost.
Note that meta 4 modules are usually about as effective as Tech II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rough estimate of costs, most modules fall somewhere near the following costs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech I, meta-0 (baseline) modules: ~50k ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meta 1-4 modules: ~10k-500k ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech II modules: ~1 million ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faction modules: ~30-100 million ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadspace modules: ~250-500 million ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officer modules: ~2-5 billion ISK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some sharp diminishing returns on cost.  An officer shield booster, for example,
costs about a thousand times as much as a Tech II booster,
but only restores about twice as much shield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fitting-strategies&#34;&gt;Fitting Strategies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s all well and good to say &amp;ldquo;a ship should be fit for a purpose&amp;rdquo;.
But what purposes should you be fitting for?
Here&amp;rsquo;s some common types of fits you&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pve&#34;&gt;PvE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, for PvE, you want to fit just enough tank to make sure you survive,
and then focus the rest of your efforts on dishing out as much damage as possible
to take out the rats faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means PvE fits tend to have as many lows filled with damage modules as they can get away with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;active-tank&#34;&gt;Active-Tank&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &amp;ldquo;Active Tank&amp;rdquo; fit focuses on repairing incoming damage faster than it&amp;rsquo;s being taken.
This lets them continue fighting as long as they can continue to run their repair modules.
This is a natural fit for PvE, where you may be in battle and taking the full attention
of the NPC pirates for long periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of an active-tank fit is its Shield Booster or Armor Repairer.
These keep the ship in fighting trim.  They are almost always supported
by at least a few Resistance-increasing modules, making them more efficient.
An active-tank fit should almost never use Shield Extenders or Armor Plates;
just as you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mix shield and armor tanks, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mix active and buffer modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second consideration is getting enough capacitor to fuel these hungry modules.
Capacitor Control Circuits, Cap Rechargers, and in a pinch Capacitor Flux Coils (for shield fits)
or Capacitor Power Relays (for armor) will increase your passive capacitor recharge,
letting you run your repair modules for longer; it&amp;rsquo;s possible to become &amp;ldquo;cap-stable&amp;rdquo;,
letting you run them indefinitely.  Typically, you won&amp;rsquo;t need to run your repair module
flat-out at all times, as killing enemy ships will soon reduce incoming damage,
so don&amp;rsquo;t get too hung up on cap-stability, but it can mean less module micromanagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, fit the best guns and as many damage modules (up to three or four) as you can
get away with.  Tracking Computers/Enhancers, Stasis Webifiers, and the like
can help you apply more damage as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;passive-tank&#34;&gt;Passive-Tank&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;Passive Tank&amp;rdquo; fit, only used by shield ships, relies on the passive recharge of your shields
regenerating them faster than you take damage.  Since the recharge rate of your shields
is based on &amp;ldquo;time to regenerate to full&amp;rdquo;, this usually involves getting a large number
of shield HP, and is about as close as PvE fits get to the &amp;ldquo;buffer tanks&amp;rdquo; of PvP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding the right mix of Shield Extenders, Shield Rechargers and Shield Hardeners
can require some fiddling.
This kind of fit typically requires going all-in, spending nearly every
low slot on Shield Power Relays and every rig on Core Defense Field Purgers,
as shield recharge modules are not stacking penalized,
and thus the multiplicative stacking makes each module more effective than the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tends to leave very few slots left for damage mods or tracking computers,
and the Shield Power Relays greatly degrade your cap recharge,
to the point where some ships struggle to even keep a shield hardener active.
However, it requires the least micromanagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If flying this kind of fit, note that shield recharge is non-linear,
and peaks at around 25-33% remaining.  If your shields dip below 25%,
you&amp;rsquo;d say that &amp;ldquo;your tank is breaking&amp;rdquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pvp&#34;&gt;PvP&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PvP fits vary widely, depending on the ship, the pilot, and the situation.
Remember the specialization mantra, and try to take fights where
you can keep your optimal situation in place and give yourself the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common distinctions, at least for solo PvP, are between &amp;ldquo;kiting&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;brawling&amp;rdquo; fits,
and &amp;ldquo;active&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;buffer&amp;rdquo; tanks.  These can be mixed whichever way; you can have an active brawler,
a buffer brawler, an active kiter, or a buffer kiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;kiting&#34;&gt;Kiting&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kiting ships focus on high speed and long-ranged weapons to keep themselves
out of reach of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s retaliation, and are a natural fit for shield ships.
They are usually more fragile and with less raw damage output than brawlers.
Kiters usually fit a Warp Disruptor for its longer range,
and a Microwarpdrive for speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If flying a kiting ship, beware of enemy ships getting within 10km of you;
that is the range of Warp Scramblers that can shut off your MWD and prevent
you from warping out, and Stasis Webifiers that will slow your ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;brawling&#34;&gt;Brawling&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brawling ships focus on raw muscle, using short-ranged weapons with high damage output
and mounting powerful tanks to survive enemy fire.
They usually have more firepower and defenses than kiters,
but their slower speed means they may have trouble catching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brawlers usually fit a Warp Scrambler to hold targets down at close range,
and often a Stasis Webifier to further prevent them from fleeing.
A Microwarpdrive is most common, to stand a chance of catching kiting ships,
but an Afterburner gives them better close-range mobility once the target is caught, as it
is not shut off by Warp Scramblers and helps them evade fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;scram-kiting&#34;&gt;Scram-Kiting&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the frigate/destroyer level, some pilots will emply a sort of hybrid of kiting and brawling
known as &amp;ldquo;scram-kiting&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of scram-kiting is to hold your enemy at the very edge of Warp Scrambler range,
and fit your ship to be optimized for dealing damage at about 10km,
and for ensuring that your ship is faster than the enemy under knife-fight conditions
and thus is able to maintain its preferred range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A warp scrambler is mandatory for scram-kiting, and a Stasis Webifier is pretty close.
Many scram-kiting fits will use afterburners, as they cannot be shut down by a scrambler
like a Microwarpdrive can, but some will use Microwarpdrives to get in range to begin kiting
and rely on their webs thereafter, or &amp;ldquo;dual-prop&amp;rdquo;, fitting both a MWD to get in range
and an Afterburner to maintain speed during the fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cruiser and battleship are sufficiently long-ranged that they can usually fight back
against a scram-kiter, so the practice is less common outside of frigates and destroyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;active-tank-1&#34;&gt;Active-Tank&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active-tanking in PvP can be a risky business, but if you choose your fights appropriately,
it can leave your opponent helpful to inflict meaningful damage on you
as you pick their ship apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in PvE, the core of the active tank is an Armor Repairer or Shield Booster,
attempting to repair damage faster than it&amp;rsquo;s taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As small-gang PvP fights tend to be shorter than PvE fights,
active-tanking PvP pilots will often use the Ancillary Armor Repairer
and Ancillary Shield Booster modules - special variants of the normal
modules, which need to be loaded with charges (&amp;ldquo;ammo&amp;rdquo;) to function most effectively,
but are much more powerful than the base modules while those charges hold out.
The charges will typically last about a minute, then take another minute to reload;
if the fight isn&amp;rsquo;t concluded by the time the module goes on reload,
the pilot using it may be in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As active armor repairers don&amp;rsquo;t show your ship down, unlike armor plates,
active tanks are a more common option for kiting armor fits than buffer tanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active-tanking is more common in solo PvP and small gangs,
where incoming damage is limited to a small number of enemy ships
and you won&amp;rsquo;t be receiving remote repairs from fleetmates.
In larger fleet battles, incoming damage from focused fire will be high enough
that an active tank will simply be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that some opponents will fit Energy Neutralizers, which can attack your ship&amp;rsquo;s
capacitor directly, leaving you unable to fuel your repair modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to fit your ship with omni resists to avoid your opponent
taking advantage of a resist hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;buffer-tank&#34;&gt;Buffer-Tank&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buffer-tanking is the practice of simply adding as many effective hitpoints (EHP)
to your ship as possible, in the hopes that by the time your opponent could chew through them all,
they&amp;rsquo;ll already be dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Armor Plate or Shield Extender is the core of a buffer-tank fit,
along with resistance modules to boost their effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to fit your ship with omni resists to avoid your opponent
taking advantage of a resist hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buffer tanks are a natural fit for fleet fights:
they let you hold up under focused fire long enough for friendly logistics ships
to lock you and begin repairing you (&amp;ldquo;catching reps&amp;rdquo;), and even without logi,
a buffer fit will usually last longer under concentrated fire than an active fit would.
Since your resists will enhance the effectiveness of these remote repairs,
higher resists can sometimes be worth a small loss in effective HP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fitting-process&#34;&gt;The Fitting Process&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after all that hurf blurf about theory - when you&amp;rsquo;re fitting a ship,
how do you go from a pile of modules and open slots to a finely-tuned weapon of war?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own approach, so the one presented here is just one of many.
Hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll give some insight into the thought process at least one pilot uses, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-one-check-bonuses-and-slots&#34;&gt;Step One: Check Bonuses And Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop is to check the bonuses on your ship (Show Info &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Traits&amp;rdquo;).
The things it has bonuses to are probably good things to focus the fit on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of slots it has will also be important in your choice (Show Info &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Fittings&amp;rdquo;.)
If its slots are heavily biased towards Mid slots, it&amp;rsquo;s probably best
as a shield or electronic warfare ship.  If Lows, it&amp;rsquo;s probably an armor boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the Drone Bay as well (Show Info &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Attributes&amp;rdquo;) - a good-sized drone bay
will give you more protection against smaller ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-two-fit-your-weapons&#34;&gt;Step Two: Fit Your Weapons&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use up your Turret or Launcher hardpoints (one or the other, if your ship has both)
by fitting as many guns as you can, of the largest caliber you have the option for.
(If you turn out not to have fitting space later, you can downsize the caliber;
starting large lets you know what you can get away with.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether to use short- or long-ranged guns depends on how you envision the fit flying.
Kiting fits usually want long-ranged weapons.
Brawling fits usually want short-ranged ones.
Note that long-ranged weapons typically take more fitting space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For drone boats (Gallente pilots, take note), your drones are your primary weapons system,
so add them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-three-fit-your-mandatory-modules&#34;&gt;Step Three: Fit Your Mandatory Modules&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every ship is going to want a propulsion module of some kind.
Whether that&amp;rsquo;s an Afterburner or a Microwarpdrive depends on your purpose.
Most PvP fits will want a MWD; PvE fits may want an Afterburner, for capacitor efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much every ship is going to want a Damage Control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any PvP fit is going to want a Warp Disruptor or Warp Scrambler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-four-fit-your-tank&#34;&gt;Step Four: Fit Your Tank&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fit whatever tank is appropriate to your ship.  They&amp;rsquo;re sometimes referred to
according to how many slots they use.  A three-slot tank is fairly common
for cruisers; frigates and destroyers often don&amp;rsquo;t have the slots to mount this,
and will use two or even just one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If buffer-tanked, this probably means a plate/extender of the largest size you can fit.
If active-tanked, this means an armor repairer/shield booster of the largest size you can fit
and which you can reasonably supply capacitor to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want a resist module to plug your worst resist hole,
then an omni-resist module for improvements across the board if you have room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of active-tanks, you should keep an eye on capacitor here too.
If your capacitor will drain exceedingly quickly, put on
capacitor-enhancing modules - rigs, cap rechargers, or capacitor boosters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-five-add-damage-mods&#34;&gt;Step Five: Add Damage Mods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throw on up to three damage mods.  Pew pew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-six-fill-out-spare-slots&#34;&gt;Step Six: Fill Out Spare Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any leftover slots, look at adding things which make your ship more effective.
Stasis Webifiers, Tracking Computers, Tracking Enhancers, utility highs, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-seven-add-rigs&#34;&gt;Step Seven: Add Rigs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rigs might have been added earlier, to plug resist holes or help with capacitor;
if not, put them in now.  If you can&amp;rsquo;t think of something,
try tank rigs (HP for buffer fits, repair cost/speed for active fits, resist for either)
or weapon rigs (if you have the spare powergrid to deal with the penalty).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-eight-add-drones&#34;&gt;Step Eight: Add Drones&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to fill up your drone bay, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t do that back in Step Two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;review-and-iterate&#34;&gt;Review And Iterate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look back over your fit.  Do you have enough CPU and Powergrid?
Does your capacitor last long enough?  Do you have enough speed to catch your targets?
Do you want to deal more damage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough CPU or Powergrid, try switching to smaller-caliber guns,
using Compact meta modules, adding fitting rigs/modules, or in a pinch,
lowering the size of your tank modules.  Feel free to ditch utility highs
if they&amp;rsquo;re putting strain on your fitting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still having trouble coming in under CPU limits, you can replace
lowslots with &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; modules: Nanofiber Internal Structure and Overdrive Injector
being the main ones, which increase speed/maneuverability at 0 cpu/grid cost.
They&amp;rsquo;re not great, but it&amp;rsquo;s better than an empty slot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s still not working, and you don&amp;rsquo;t have any more modules that you can swap out
without degrading the fit to the point of unusability, it&amp;rsquo;s back to the drawing board;
the fit just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to demonstrate, let&amp;rsquo;s see an example of how it all comes together.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try and walk you through the mental process I was using while
creating one of the fits used in this guide: the &amp;ldquo;Improved Cormorant&amp;rdquo; fit for Caldari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the Cormorant hull:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object type=&#34;image/svg+xml&#34; data=&#34;https://o.smium.org/api/convert/118655/svg/118655-cormorant-bare-hull.svg&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://o.smium.org/loadout/118655&#34;&gt;View Cormorant (Bare Hull) on Osmium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-one-check-bonuses-and-slots-1&#34;&gt;Step One: Check Bonuses And Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the Cormorant&amp;rsquo;s Traits, we see that it has a double bonus to Optimal Range,
and a bonus to Tracking, for Small Hybrids.  To leverage that bonus, we&amp;rsquo;re going to
make it a railgun sniper.  The Tracking bonus will help with flexibility a bit, but
isn&amp;rsquo;t the focus of the fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cormorant&amp;rsquo;s slot layout is 8/3/2 (high/med/low), with 7 turret hardpoints and no drones.
This means a shield tank, as two lows isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for a solid armor tank at the best of times -
and we&amp;rsquo;ll want that space for damage mods.  Besides, Caldari primarily shield-tank anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-two-fit-your-weapons-1&#34;&gt;Step Two: Fit Your Weapons&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small railguns come in 75mm, 125mm, and 150mm caliber.  We&amp;rsquo;ll want to try to fit 150mm if we can.
Opening up the 150mm Railgun I&amp;rsquo;s Variations tab reminds us that the meta 4 version is the
150mm Prototype Gauss Gun.  In the Market, it has an estimated price of 216k ISK;
that&amp;rsquo;s not too expensive, so we&amp;rsquo;ll use that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: 7x &lt;code&gt;150mm Prototype Gauss Gun&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 114 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 18.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would try to fit Tech II guns, but this character doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the skills to use them,
so that&amp;rsquo;s out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-three-fit-your-mandatory-modules-1&#34;&gt;Step Three: Fit Your Mandatory Modules&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On goes the Damage Control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For prop, looking at our fitting room, I can see we&amp;rsquo;re already a bit low on grid.
We use an Afterburner, for its cheaper fitting costs.
Its lower capacitor costs are also of interest, and we use an Enduring afterburner
to lower them still further, as I&amp;rsquo;m thinking ahead to Step Four; see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a PvP fit, so we don&amp;rsquo;t add a warp disruptor or scrambler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Damage Control II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;1MN Monopropellant Enduring Afterburner I&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 69 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 7.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-four-fit-your-tank-1&#34;&gt;Step Four: Fit Your Tank&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this fit was designed for early PvE, we&amp;rsquo;re making it an active-tanker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d usually prefer to buffer-tank a destroyer,
but this is a better fit for the purpose of the guide.
Destroyer capacitors aren&amp;rsquo;t really suited for extended boosting,
but long missions with a buffer fit require repeatedly warping out and back in,
which is a hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, we throw on a Medium Shield Booster, the largest boosting module frigates
and destroyers can usually handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also add an Anti-EM Screen Reinforcer rig to shore up the EM resist hole -
they&amp;rsquo;re cheap, and they don&amp;rsquo;t use a precious midslot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: Medium Shield Booster II&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: Small Anti-EM Screen Reinforcer I&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 11 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: -5.4 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;record scratch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm, that&amp;rsquo;s a problem.  We&amp;rsquo;re exceeding our powergrid,
our CPU is almost exhausted while we&amp;rsquo;ve still got two slots to fill,
and we can barely run the shield booster for 30 seconds before our capacitor runs dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it was just the CPU &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; powergrid, I would probably try and use a fitting module
or rig to make up the difference.  If it was just both of those, I would probably
try downsizing the gun caliber to 125mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But combined with the capacitor pressure, and the difficulty we&amp;rsquo;re going to have in making
up for that with our limited remaining slots, I decide the best option is to just use
a smaller shield booster instead.  It&amp;rsquo;s just as efficient, it just has lower maximum throughput;
if we&amp;rsquo;re limited by capacitor anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REMOVE: &lt;code&gt;Medium Shield Booster II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Small Shield Booster II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 40 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 4.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-five-add-damage-mods-1&#34;&gt;Step Five: Add Damage Mods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One free lowslot, one mod.  Pop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Magnetic Field Stabilizer II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 10 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 3.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-six-fill-out-spare-slots-1&#34;&gt;Step Six: Fill Out Spare Slots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve still got a midslot and two rigs to work with.
Our capacitor&amp;rsquo;s a bit lacking to run the Shield Booster for extended periods,
so let&amp;rsquo;s try to improve that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capacitor Boosters are a very slot-efficient way to keep modules running;
however, they require hauling around bulky Cap Booster charges as ammo,
and I don&amp;rsquo;t like having to continually resupply while missioning -
or running out mid-mission.  We&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; far off from being able to run
the booster for long periods; let&amp;rsquo;s try improving passive recharge instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Cap Recharger II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: &lt;strong&gt;-4.3&lt;/strong&gt; of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 2.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm&amp;hellip;we&amp;rsquo;re a bit under on CPU.  Not by much, though.  Let&amp;rsquo;s keep going for now, and come back
to see what we can fiddle with later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-seven-add-rigs-1&#34;&gt;Step Seven: Add Rigs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could still use some more capacitor, and cap rigs have no real trade-offs aside from their cost.
Let&amp;rsquo;s add a couple of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Capacitor Control Circuit I&lt;/code&gt; x2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: &lt;strong&gt;-4.3&lt;/strong&gt; of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 2.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-eight-add-drones-1&#34;&gt;Step Eight: Add Drones&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No drone bay.  Easy step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;review-and-iterate-1&#34;&gt;Review And Iterate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the fit seems to have pretty much come together.  We can run the shield booster
indefinitely if we&amp;rsquo;re not using anything else, and can keep it active enough of the time
to feel comfortable while using the guns and the afterburner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s still the matter of that CPU deficiency, though; we need to resolve that.
We could spend a slot on a Co-Processor or Processor Overclocking rig,
but losing the slot would be a big blow to the ship&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see if there&amp;rsquo;s something we can meta down instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to meta down the damage control or the damage mod if we can help it,
as the tech II versions of those give nice, strong benefits.  Same for the shield booster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could maybe drop the guns to a different meta level&amp;hellip;but looking at their CPU costs,
the meta 4 guns we have installed are the cheapest until you get all the way down to meta 1.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to lose 15% damage if I can avoid it, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That leaves the afterburner and the cap recharger.  Fingers crossed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with an Enduring afterburner, to save on capacitor costs.
If we swap to a Compact afterburner instead, we can save&amp;hellip;two points of CPU and one grid.
Not good enough, but it might help in conjunction with something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the cap recharger.  Save me, meta cap recharger, you&amp;rsquo;re my only hope!
Going from the Tech II cap recharger to the Compact meta version saves us&amp;hellip;seven CPU.  Huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REMOVE: &lt;code&gt;Cap Recharger II&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ADD: &lt;code&gt;Eutectic Compact Cap Recharger&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU REMAINING: 2.4 of 240&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POWERGRID REMAINING: 2.6 of 81.6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had any other Compact modules on the fit, I might stop now and review
whether I could spend my scant remaining CPU and grid to upgrade one of them
to a variant such as Enduring or Restrained.  But I don&amp;rsquo;t, so I won&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied with the fit, we load ammo, hop in, and prepare to bring 150mm of antimatter justice
to any pirate that stands in our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;object type=&#34;image/svg+xml&#34; data=&#34;https://o.smium.org/api/convert/118480/svg/118480-alpha-clone---improved-cormorant.svg?privatetoken=988938429179887616&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://o.smium.org/loadout/private/118480/988938429179887616&#34;&gt;View Alpha Clone - Improved Cormorant on Osmium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rookie Chat FAQ</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/rookie-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/rookie-faq/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A list of questions frequently asked in the Rookie Help channel
and their associated answers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-do-i-split-a-stack-of-items&#34;&gt;How do I split a stack of items?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold shift and drag the stack of items, then drop it somewhere else. A dialog window
will appear asking how many you wish to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;where-is-the-mini-skill-injector&#34;&gt;Where is the Mini Skill Injector?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;Y&lt;/kbd&gt; to open the Redeem window. It should be in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-closed-the-career-agents-list-how-do-i-get-it-back&#34;&gt;I closed the Career Agents list, how do I get it back?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;F12&lt;/kbd&gt; to open the &amp;lsquo;Help&amp;rsquo; window, then click &amp;lsquo;Show Career Agents&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;i-bought-something-but-it-s-not-in-my-item-hangar-where-is-it&#34;&gt;I bought something but it&amp;rsquo;s not in my item hangar. Where is it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are you purchased an item listed from another station. Press
&lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;T&lt;/kbd&gt; to open the Assets window and figure out which station
you bought it in, then fly to that station to pick it up. Purchasing an item does
not magically move it to your current station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-can-i-find-which-station-one-of-my-items-is-in&#34;&gt;How can I find which station one of my items is in?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;T&lt;/kbd&gt; to open the Assets window which lists all of your assets
by station. Note that the assets window only updates once every ~5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-do-i-use-the-scanning-interface&#34;&gt;How do I use the scanning interface?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EVE has a set of tutorial videos to help you figure this out. Press &lt;kbd&gt;F12&lt;/kbd&gt; to
open the &amp;lsquo;Help&amp;rsquo; window, then select the &amp;lsquo;Tutorial Videos&amp;rsquo; tab. Scroll down to &amp;lsquo;Exploration&amp;rsquo;
and watch the scanning videos there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-better-to-sell-ore-directly-or-reprocess-it-and-sell-the-minerals&#34;&gt;Is it better to sell ore directly or reprocess it and sell the minerals?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For new players it is generally better to sell the ore itself, because new players
will not have the level of skills required to efficiently refine ore into the full
value equivalent of minerals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-are-the-different-types-of-ore-and-where-can-i-find-them&#34;&gt;What are the different types of ore and where can I find them?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cerlestes has an &lt;a href=&#34;http://ore.cerlestes.de/#site:ore&#34;&gt;excellent ore chart&lt;/a&gt;. For even
more detail you can look at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Asteroids_and_Ore&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Asteroids and Ore&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-does-this-asteroid-belt-not-have-any-asteroids&#34;&gt;Why does this asteroid belt not have any asteroids?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asteroid belts respawn once a day during the daily downtime (11:00 EVE time). In
highly-populated systems individual belts may get mined out quickly - try traveling
to another system if all of the belts in your current system have been mined out,
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/CSMNCc7.png&#34;&gt;going to an asteroid anomaly&lt;/a&gt; if there are any
listed in the Probe Scanner window (&lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;P&lt;/kbd&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-do-i-bookmark-a-point-in-space-rather-than-a-specific-thing&#34;&gt;How do I bookmark a point in space rather than a specific thing?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;B&lt;/kbd&gt; to bring up the bookmark creation dialog for your
current position in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-can-t-my-guns-hit-this-pirate&#34;&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t my guns hit this pirate?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably either too far away (outside of your gun&amp;rsquo;s Optimal Range)
or too close (and your gun turret can&amp;rsquo;t rotate fast enough to track the
moving target).  Try staying at about your gun&amp;rsquo;s Optimal Range, and if
still having accuracy trouble, try using Keep At Range instead of Orbit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-does-a-module-has-run-out-of-charges-mean&#34;&gt;What does &amp;lsquo;a module has run out of charges&amp;rsquo; mean?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your weapons probably need to be loaded with ammunition.
Right-click your weapon, click &amp;ldquo;Show Info&amp;rdquo;, and see &amp;ldquo;Used With&amp;rdquo; for ammo types you can use.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have them, buy some off the Market.
Once you have some in your cargo hold, click-and-drag it over your gun&amp;rsquo;s icon,
or while in space, right-click the gun&amp;rsquo;s icon in your HUD and select the ammo type to load.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your First Wormhole</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/wormholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/wormholes/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve just scanned down a wormhole for the first time, and you&amp;rsquo;re sitting next to it
in space, wondering&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;should I jump in?&amp;rdquo; You may have heard that wormholes are
dangerous places, but perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve also heard that they contain lucrative exploration sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these are true - wormholes definitely hold to the maxim of &amp;ldquo;nothing risked, nothing
gained.&amp;rdquo; So this guide is going to walk you through the basics of going on the adventure
that is entering wormhole space. This is not a complete guide to everything wormholes -
for that, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to look at the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Wormholes&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Wormholes&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;.
This is just enough that you can hopefully have an interesting trip without making
avoidable rookie mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-ship-should-i-take-into-a-wormhole&#34;&gt;What ship should I take into a wormhole?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re going to want to be in an exploration frigate for your first trip into a wormhole.
Chances are you&amp;rsquo;re already in one (that&amp;rsquo;s probably what you scanned it in), but if you&amp;rsquo;re
not, we recommend switching to one. Wormholes involve a bunch of scanning once you&amp;rsquo;re
inside them as well, so you want to be in the right ship for the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices note&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Not sure what your race&amp;rsquo;s exploration frigate is? Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/upgrading-ships/&#34;&gt;Upgrade to a New Ship&lt;/a&gt;
chapter. The recommended exploration frigate fits there are suitable for wormhole exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Whatever fit you&amp;rsquo;re using, you want to make sure you have at least 3 things fit and loaded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x &lt;code&gt;Core Probe Launcher I&lt;/code&gt; or another probe launcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8x &lt;code&gt;Core Scanner Probe I&lt;/code&gt; or some other core probe variety.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x &lt;code&gt;Relic Analyzer I&lt;/code&gt; (Relic sites are what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for to make ISK.)`&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing spare probes is not a bad idea, but also by no means required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;which-wormhole-should-i-enter&#34;&gt;Which wormhole should I enter?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can determine some information about a wormhole without ever jumping through it.
After you&amp;rsquo;ve warped to the wormhole, right-click on it and choose Show Info. The
description window that pops up will tell you &lt;strong&gt;four important things to know&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;where-does-it-lead&#34;&gt;Where does it lead?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the kind of space on the other side of the wormhole. You can tell this
from the line of the description that begins with &lt;em&gt;This wormhole seems to lead into&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it says it leads to &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;low&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;null&amp;rdquo; security space, the other side is a regular
highsec, lowsec, or nullsec system somewhere else in the known galaxy. This is not what you
are looking for (though you could certainly try peeking through it to see where it leads).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it says it leads &amp;ldquo;into &lt;em&gt;dangerous&lt;/em&gt; unknown parts of space&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;into &lt;em&gt;deadly&lt;/em&gt; unknown
parts of space&amp;rdquo;, the other side is a Class 4 or higher wormhole. These are also not what
you are looking for because any relic sites in them will have sleeper enemies defending them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it says only that it leads &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;into unknown parts of space&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;ve found what you&amp;rsquo;re looking
for - this wormhole leads into a Class 1, 2, or 3 wormhole which is where the relic sites
you&amp;rsquo;re looking for can spawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-about-to-time-out&#34;&gt;Is it about to time out?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wormholes, unlike stargates, come and go. A wormhole generally doesn&amp;rsquo;t last for more than 24
hours from when it initially spawned. The thing you want to look for here is whether or not
the wormhole description mentions that it is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;nearing the end of its natural lifetime.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see that in the description, the wormhole could disappear at any moment. If you don&amp;rsquo;t
see that in the description (even if the description talks about decay), the wormhole has at
least a couple of hours remaining before it goes end-of-life (&amp;ldquo;EOL&amp;rdquo;) and times out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only enter wormholes that are not end-of-life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-about-to-destabilize&#34;&gt;Is it about to destabilize?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to their time limit, wormholes also have a limit on how much total ship mass can
pass through them before they destabilize and disappear. The description on the wormhole will
have one of three phrases which indicate how close they are to destabilizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the description states that the wormhole is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;on the verge of collapse&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, the wormhole
has less than 10% of its mass limit remaining and may disappear at any time. This is generally
referred to as a &amp;ldquo;crit hole&amp;rdquo;. You want to avoid entering these holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it states that the wormhole &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;has had its stability reduced, but not to a critical degree&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
then the wormhole has somewhere between 10-50% of its mass limit remaining. Be wary of entering
these wormholes because the reduced state indicates that there&amp;rsquo;s been a fair amount of other
traffic through the hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing you want to find is a wormhole that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;has not yet had its stability disrupted&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.
Wormholes with this in the description have 50% or more of their mass limit remaining and
so are unlikely to destabilize of natural causes any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only enter wormholes that have plenty of mass remaining.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-size-of-ships-does-it-allow&#34;&gt;What size of ships does it allow?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some wormholes have limits on the size of ships that can pass through them. Since you&amp;rsquo;re
in a frigate, you can go through any wormhole, but it can sometimes be useful to know
what kinds of other ships could also go through. This is a little less important though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the wormhole says that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;only the smallest ships&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; can pass through, then only ships
with the mass of a destroyer or frigate can go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Up to medium size ships&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; means anything battlecruiser-sized or smaller. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Larger ships&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;
means anything battleship-sized or smaller, and &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Very large ships&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; means nearly every
kind of ship can go through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Small wormholes are good for you, since fewer other players&amp;rsquo; ships can go through them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;okay-let-s-go&#34;&gt;Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s go!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve checked that this is a good wormhole to enter, it&amp;rsquo;s time to begin the
expedition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First things first:&lt;/strong&gt; right-click the wormhole and select Save Location&amp;hellip; to make
a bookmark for the entrance. Name it whatever you&amp;rsquo;d like. It&amp;rsquo;ll show up in People &amp;amp;
Places (&lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;/kbd&gt;E&lt;/kbd&gt;) in the Places tab, and also when you right-click
in empty space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open your Directional Scanner window (&lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;D&lt;/kbd&gt;) and make sure that
both the Range and Angle sliders are set full right (the Angle should read 360). In
Wormholes your d-scan will be your best friend for staying safe. Inside wormholes,
players don&amp;rsquo;t show up in the Local channel member list unless they say something (and
they won&amp;rsquo;t). So d-scan will be your only warning of players in the system before they
appear next to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re about to enter the wormhole. Read through the next few steps first so you&amp;rsquo;re
ready to do them together without having to look back at this guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Right-click the wormhole and select Enter Wormhole. Your ship will jump through
the wormhole to the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you load into the system on the other side of the wormhole, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t move yet&lt;/strong&gt;.
Like jumping through a stargate, going through a wormhole gives you 60 seconds
of automatic cloaking so that you can get your bearings. (The timer appears in
the upper left corner as a circled blue ship.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you&amp;rsquo;re still cloaked, right-click on this side of the wormhole and bookmark
it as well. If you don&amp;rsquo;t bookmark it you&amp;rsquo;ll have to scan it down again later to
find your way back out, with no way of knowing for sure if it&amp;rsquo;s the same wormhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, still not breaking your cloak, press the Scan button on your d-scan window to
refresh the results. Hopefully you won&amp;rsquo;t see much aside from celestials like planets
and customs offices. &lt;strong&gt;If you see any ships or probes on d-scan, go back through the
wormhole.&lt;/strong&gt; You&amp;rsquo;re in a scanning frigate, and you&amp;rsquo;re not looking for a fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point your 60 seconds of jump cloak is probably about to expire. It&amp;rsquo;s time
to make a safe spot. Right-click in space and go to the Planets menu, then pick a
random planet from the list and warp to it. As you&amp;rsquo;re starting to warp, press
&lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;B&lt;/kbd&gt; to bring up the bookmark creation screen, and type
in a name like &amp;ldquo;mid safe&amp;rdquo;. &lt;strong&gt;While in the middle of your warp, press the Save button.&lt;/strong&gt;
This will create a bookmark in a spot in empty space somewhere between the wormhole
and the planet you warped to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices note&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Bookmarks created via &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;-&lt;kbd&gt;B&lt;/kbd&gt; are located where you were when
you pressed Save, &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; where you were when you opened the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve landed at the planet, right-click in empty space and warp back to you
mid safe bookmark. When you land there, press the Scan button on your d-scan again
to make sure there still aren&amp;rsquo;t any ships or probes on scan. If anything has appeared,
warp back to the wormhole exit you bookmarked earlier and leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(If you were reading ahead before, this is probably where you can go ahead and
do the things mentioned above.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since as an alpha clone you can&amp;rsquo;t use a cloaking device, this mid safe (and others
you create like it) is your best defense against hostiles in a wormhole. Players
that want to locate you will have to use combat probes to scan you down. By frequently
refreshing d-scan, you can spot these probes and leave before they get a chance to
attack you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to keep refreshing d-scan every 10-15 seconds. Experienced players can probe a
ship down in 15 seconds or less and will recall their probes once they&amp;rsquo;ve finished.
You can bind refreshing d-scan to a key in the Esc menu to make it easier to refresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to launch your own probes to start scanning the signatures in the system.
Note that your own probes will appear on your d-scan listing, so don&amp;rsquo;t be spooked by
probes that belong to yourself - but make sure to watch for any additional sets of probes
that might appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-am-i-looking-for&#34;&gt;What am I looking for?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you already had to scan down the entrance wormhole, this guide won&amp;rsquo;t cover
how to scan down a signature. Instead, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.
Amongst all of the signatures in the system, you&amp;rsquo;re looking for the &lt;strong&gt;relic&lt;/strong&gt; sites.
In particular, you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a very specific kind of relic site, the ones
with a pirate faction in the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of relic sites in Class 1-3 wormholes: faction and sleeper.
Sleeper relic sites have sleeper enemies in them; you don&amp;rsquo;t want those because
you can&amp;rsquo;t fight sleepers. Faction relic sites have no NPC enemies - they&amp;rsquo;re just
like relic sites in normal space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faction relic sites have a faction in the site name: &lt;strong&gt;Sansha,
Guristas, Serpentis, Angels, Blood&lt;/strong&gt;. Sleeper relic sites have words like &amp;ldquo;Unsecured&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Perimeter&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;Sleeper&amp;rdquo; in
the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-found-a-faction-relic-site-now-what&#34;&gt;I found a faction relic site, now what?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming d-scan is still clear, warp to it and start hacking! Continue to keep an eye
on (and refresh) d-scan as you&amp;rsquo;re hacking, and if you see anything new show up make
sure to warp out back to either your mid safe or the wormhole exit. If everything
goes well you should loot some salvage from each of the cans you successfully hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the site you can warp back to your mid safe and keep scanning,
or exit the wormhole with your newly acquired loot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your first wormhole expedition I recommend leaving once you&amp;rsquo;ve either finished
all of the relic sites or have at least 20M worth of loot, but it&amp;rsquo;s up to you how
long you want to stay. Do note that scanner probes will expire if you leave them
in space for longer than an hour, so if they&amp;rsquo;ve been out for a while you&amp;rsquo;ll want
to recall them and re-launch to refresh their expiry timer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-did-it&#34;&gt;I did it!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing your first wormhole expedition! The salvage you&amp;rsquo;ve
acquired is generally fairly easy to sell in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/hubs/&#34;&gt;market hub&lt;/a&gt; - the
buy orders are usually pretty good there. If you happen to have an extrodinarily
large amount of valuable salvage in your cargohold (40M or more) make sure to be
extra careful on your way to the trade hub to avoid getting suicide ganked - don&amp;rsquo;t
autopilot and don&amp;rsquo;t go AFK or sit still on gates. Once you reach the market hub,
sell your loot and enjoy the ISK!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>