<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjust Your Skill Queue</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a better sense of what you&amp;rsquo;re interested in doing in EVE,
it&amp;rsquo;s time to adjust your skill queue to train the skills that will help you
with your chosen activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few pages will walk through various aspects you might consider
for skill training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/core/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/core/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some skills that basically every player will want to train
because they&amp;rsquo;re useful no matter what ship you&amp;rsquo;re flying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hull Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; Level IV allows you to use the better Damage Control II
module, which is a significant improvement over the basic version of the module,
making your ship more survivable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shield Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; Level IV allows you to use better shield-related modules, improving
your shield-based defenses. (Caldari, Gallente, and Minmatar only. If you&amp;rsquo;re
using ships that focus on armor defenses, you can skip this for now.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Energy Grid Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; Level III allows you to use a lot of new capacitor-related
modules, making it easier to create ship fits that don&amp;rsquo;t run out of capacitor
quite as easily. Level IV lets you upgrade many of those modules to their better
tech 2 variants, further improving capacitor benefits. You&amp;rsquo;ll definitely want to
train III, and eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll want to train IV, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the ships you&amp;rsquo;re flying have drone bays, &lt;code&gt;Drones&lt;/code&gt; Level III and
&lt;code&gt;Light Drone Operation&lt;/code&gt; Level I are highly recommended so that your ships
can use at least light combat drones, which provide some additional combat
capability for any ship with a drone bay. If you decide to keep using
drones you&amp;rsquo;ll eventually want to train &lt;code&gt;Drones&lt;/code&gt; Level V so that you
can launch up to 5 drones (assuming the ship allows it).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combat Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/combat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/combat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a path that involves fighting other ships, here are some
skills you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to train:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-combat-skills&#34;&gt;General Combat Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Weapon Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; Level IV allows you to use the tech 2 versions of
the damage bonus modules: Heat Sink II for lasers, Ballistic Control System
II for missiles, Magnetic Field Stabilizer II for hybrid weapons, Gyrostabilizer
II for projectile weapons, and Drone Damage Amplifier II for drones. Better
modules means more damage means faster ISK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;drone-combat-skills&#34;&gt;Drone Combat Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your ships have drone bays, you&amp;rsquo;ll also want to further train your drone skills.
&lt;code&gt;Light Drone Operation&lt;/code&gt; Level IV is a good investment as the increased drone
damage will benefit any ship with a drone bay. Eventually you will want to train
the other drone support skills as well to improve the performance of your drones
even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drones&lt;/code&gt; allows you to control more drones simultaneously.  If flying ships with
at least 25 Mbit/sec of drone bandwidth (enough to control five light drones),
you will want to train this to level V when time allows.  Level IV is required
to train many of the support skills, and Level III is required to use drones at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drone Navigation&lt;/code&gt; increases the flight speed of your drones, meaning less time spent
waiting for them to reach their target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drone Avionics&lt;/code&gt; increases the range at which you can command your drones to attack.
Training this to level III should be sufficient to allow a frigate or destroyer
to command drones out to its maximum lock range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drone Durability&lt;/code&gt; increases all your drones&amp;rsquo; HP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Drone Interfacing&lt;/code&gt; provides a substantial damage boost to all drones.
However, it requires Drones V to be trained as a pre-requisite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;shield-skills&#34;&gt;Shield Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re flying ships that use shields as their main form of defense, you&amp;rsquo;ll want
to train these skills to improve your shield defenses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shield Operation&lt;/code&gt; Level IV improves the rate at which you&amp;rsquo;re shields recharge and is
also required in order to train the various Shield Compensation skills, each of which
improves one of types of shield resistance for your ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shield Compensation&lt;/code&gt; Level III minimizes the cost of your shield booster module,
allowing you to run it longer for more boosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shield Management&lt;/code&gt; increases your total shield amount, you should train it as high
as possible for your race when you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;armor-skills&#34;&gt;Armor Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re flying ships that use armor as their main form of defense, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to
train these skills to improve your armor defenses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Repair Systems&lt;/code&gt; Level III allows you to use a Small Armor Repairer II, which provides
more repairs than the basic armor repairer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gunnery-skills&#34;&gt;Gunnery Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re flying ships that use turrets as their main weapon system, you&amp;rsquo;ll want
to train these skills to improve your turret weapons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Surgical Strike&lt;/code&gt; offers a straight up bonus to all turret damage. You&amp;rsquo;ll want
to train it as high as possible for maximum damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rapid Firing&lt;/code&gt; increases the fire rate of your turrets, increasing your
overall damage output. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to train it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Motion Prediction&lt;/code&gt; increases the tracking speed of your turrets, making
it less likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll miss. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to eventually train it as high
as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sharpshooter&lt;/code&gt; increases the optimal range of your turrets by a percentage, extending
the distance at which they are most effective. (This benefits projectile turrets
less due to their low base optimal range, so Minmatar alpha clone pilots can wait
to train this skill.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Trajectory Analysis&lt;/code&gt; increases the falloff distance of your turrets by a percentage,
extending the distance at which they are effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Controlled Bursts&lt;/code&gt; decreases the capacitor cost of firing your turrets. Minmatar alpha
clone pilots can ignore this skill since projectile turrets don&amp;rsquo;t use capacitor. For
everyone else, it&amp;rsquo;s generally a good idea to train this skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;missile-skills&#34;&gt;Missile Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re flying ships that use missiles as their main weapon system, you&amp;rsquo;ll want
to train these skills to improve your missile launchers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Light Missiles&lt;/code&gt; is required to use light missile launchers and provides a straight
up bonus to light missile damage for each level. Train it to at least Level I, and
if you plan to keep flying missile-using frigates for a while, train it as high as
possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Missile Launcher Operation&lt;/code&gt; improves your launcher rate of fire, increasing your
overall damage output. Train it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Warhead Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; provides a straight up bonus to missile damage that stacks
with the bonus from other skills. Train it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rapid Launch&lt;/code&gt; increases your launcher rate of fire and stacks with the bonuses
from Missile Launcher Operation, increasing your overall damage output. Train it
as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Missile Projection&lt;/code&gt; makes your missiles fly faster, which means they also fly
further. It&amp;rsquo;s generally a good idea to eventually train it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Missile Bombardment&lt;/code&gt; allows your missiles to fly longer, which means they also fly
further. It&amp;rsquo;s generally a good idea to eventually train it as high as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Missile speed and missile flight time stack multiplicatively with one another when
it comes to determining overall maximum range, so train both Projection and
Bombardment equally for best results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Target Navigation Prediction&lt;/code&gt; makes your missiles apply a greater percentage of
their maximum potential damage to fast-moving targets. If you often find yourself
struggling to do much damage to the smaller, faster ships you&amp;rsquo;re shooting, train
this skill to help with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;medium-weapon-skills&#34;&gt;Medium Weapon Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the path you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen involves upgrading to cruisers and battlecruisers, you&amp;rsquo;ll
also want to train for medium-sized weapons to put on them. This means some subset
of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Medium Energy Turret&lt;/code&gt; (Amarr)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Medium Hybrid Turret&lt;/code&gt; (Caldari, Gallente)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Medium Projectile Turret&lt;/code&gt; (Minmatar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Heavy Missiles&lt;/code&gt; (Caldari, Minmatar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Heavy Assault Missiles&lt;/code&gt; (Caldari, Minmatar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Medium Drone Operation&lt;/code&gt; (Amarr, Gallente)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/exploration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to try out exploration further, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to train the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-scanning-skills&#34;&gt;General Scanning Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Astrometric Acquisition&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Astrometric Rangefinding&lt;/code&gt; make it easier to
scan down cosmic signatures. You&amp;rsquo;ll want to train them both to Level II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also make sure to train your racial Frigate skill all the way to Level IV,
as that will increase the effectiveness of your exploration ship&amp;rsquo;s bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploration-skills&#34;&gt;Exploration Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Archeology&lt;/code&gt; increases your Virus Coherence (&amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo;) when hacking relic
site containers. Training this to Level III will help you successfully
complete hacks more often. &lt;code&gt;Hacking&lt;/code&gt; is the equivalent for data sites,
but it&amp;rsquo;s less of a priority since relic sites are the better of the two.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/mining/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to further explore mining, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to train these skills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-mining-skills&#34;&gt;General Mining Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mining Frigate&lt;/code&gt; Level IV - as an alpha clone, the best ship available to you
for mining is the Venture. Training up this skill will improve the Venture&amp;rsquo;s
mining bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ore-mining&#34;&gt;Ore Mining&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mining&lt;/code&gt; Level IV adds a little more yield to your mining lasers, so each cycle
will obtain a bit more ore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mining Upgrades&lt;/code&gt; Level IV lets you use a Mining Laser Upgrade II which provides
the best bonus to mining lasers available in a module. (Even just Level I will
let you use the basic version of the module for a smaller bonus.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gas-harvesting&#34;&gt;Gas Harvesting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want, you can also explore gas harvesting, which is very similar to ore
mining but is done at special gas sites which have to be scanned down with probes.
If you want to harvest gas, train &lt;code&gt;Gas Cloud Harvesting&lt;/code&gt; Level II and equip your
Venture with a pair of gas harvesters instead of mining lasers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skill book for Gas Harvesting is somewhat expensive, and the gas harvesters
themselves are also a little spendy. However, the gas mined with them will often
fetch a higher price than ore would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices note&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the valuable gas sites occur in dangerous areas - lowsec and wormhole space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ship Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/ship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/ship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone will want to train their race&amp;rsquo;s Frigate skill up to at least
Level III, as this both improves the effectiveness of their frigate&amp;rsquo;s ship bonuses
and also unlocks additional classes of ships for training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the path you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen involves flying frigates a lot, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want
to go a bit further and train the skill to Level IV to further improve your
ship bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the path you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen involves upgrading to higher classes of ships, you&amp;rsquo;ll
probably want to start training towards cruisers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Skills</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/training/trade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen a path that involves lots of buying and selling things on
the market, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to improve your trading skills. You can skip these
skills if chosing a path that doesn&amp;rsquo;t focus on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Trade&lt;/code&gt; Level III will maximize the number of simultaneous buy and sell orders
you can have posted on the market at once as an alpha clone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Broker Relations&lt;/code&gt; Level II will slightly reduce the fees involved in creating
market orders. It&amp;rsquo;s a small difference, but over time that can add up to a lot
of ISK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>