<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Market-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:35:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Use the Market</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:35:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;searching-the-market&#34;&gt;Searching the Market&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When following this guide you&amp;rsquo;ll almost always be wanting particular items
from the market. The fastest way to find those items is use the search box.
Copy the name of the item and paste it into the box to the left of the
&amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; button, then click that button. A list of results (most likely
with only a single item, but sometimes more) will appear beneath.
Click the item in the result list to see where that item is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;buying-items&#34;&gt;Buying Items&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When viewing market listings for a particular item you will see two sections:
Sellers and Buyers. We&amp;rsquo;re going to concentrate on the Sellers section for now
because we want to buy items from those Sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sort-your-sellers-list&#34;&gt;Sort your sellers list&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all: &lt;strong&gt;make sure your sellers are sorted by Price, ascending&lt;/strong&gt;.
This means that the price column should be the only column with an upwards-pointing
triangle on the right side of it. Try clicking the price column header to change the sorting.
Click the price column as many times as you need until it&amp;rsquo;s sorting properly. This is
to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not accidentally buying a highly overpriced version of the item
just because it happens to be a system closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorting by price also helps you avoid a scam where someone lists an item for what seems to
be a cheaper price, but actually has a few extra zeroes on the end - so you wind up
paying 1 million isk instead of 1 thousand isk or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;look-at-the-availability&#34;&gt;Look at the availability&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, look through the list. The first column, &lt;strong&gt;Jumps&lt;/strong&gt;, shows you how far you&amp;rsquo;ll need to go
to pick up the item after buying it. When you buy an item, you buy it in the station where
it was listed - not necessarily in your current station. So if the &amp;lsquo;Jumps&amp;rsquo; column reads
&amp;lsquo;5&amp;rsquo;, that means that after buying the item you&amp;rsquo;ll need to jump through 5 stargates to reach
the system where you bought the item. If the jumps column says &amp;lsquo;System&amp;rsquo; it means the item
is located in your current system but a different station, and if it says &amp;lsquo;Station&amp;rsquo; it means
that it&amp;rsquo;s listed in the same station you&amp;rsquo;re currently in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;strong&gt;Quantity&lt;/strong&gt; - displaying how many items are available via that seller. If you want
to buy more, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get them from multiple sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Price&lt;/strong&gt; column lists the price per unit being offered; if the listed price is 100.00
ISK and you want to buy 50 of the item, you&amp;rsquo;ll wind up paying 5000 ISK total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see exactly which station the items are listed from in the &lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt; column. This is
important - before buying items in another system, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to check to make sure
you can get there without having to go through low-security space (0.4 and below). Otherwise
you might get ganked on the way. You can right-click on a particular seller and choose
Location -&amp;gt; Set Destination to a set an autopilot course to it, and then look at the colored
dots that the autopilot shows you: if any of them are orange or red, don&amp;rsquo;t buy from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Hubs</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/hubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:35:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/market/hubs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s technically possible to sell items from any station in EVE, the vast majority
of items are bought and sold at a small set of stations referred to as &amp;ldquo;market hubs&amp;rdquo;.
These stations will have literally thousands of times more items available than your
average station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Jita IV - Moon 4 - Caldari Navy Assembly Plant&lt;/code&gt; is the most popular market hub. It is located in Caldari space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Amarr VIII (Oris) - Emperor Family Academy&lt;/code&gt; is also fairly popular, and is located in Amarr space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dodixie IX - Moon 20 - Federation Navy Assembly Plant&lt;/code&gt; is the largest Gallente market hub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rens VI - Moon 8 - Brutor Tribe Treasury&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Hek VIII - Moon 12 - Boundless Creation Factory&lt;/code&gt; are the largest Minmatar market hubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit any of these hubs no matter the race of your character, but your starting system will likely be much
closer to the market hubs in your own race&amp;rsquo;s space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>