<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New-goals-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in New-goals-rsses on The Alpha&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Choose Your Adventure</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVE is a sandbox game, so there&amp;rsquo;s no particular progression for you to follow
once you&amp;rsquo;re past the tutorials. It&amp;rsquo;s time to figure out what you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the career agents&amp;rsquo; mission chains you should have a
little bit better sense of how some of the various EVE activities work. The
following pages will provide you with some more details about various options
for what you can do in EVE, and point you in the right direction for each of
them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/exploration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploration involves using probes to scan down signatures to find relic
and data sites, and then hacking the containers in those sites to obtain
valuable loot. You can also find wormholes which connect to systems that
are completely unreachable via normal stargates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relic sites are the best source of reliable income from exploration - data
sites tend to have fewer valuable items, though occasionally you may find
a very valuable item such as a rare blueprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to pursue exploration, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to use a ship with scanning
and hacking bonuses, like the exploration frigates from each faction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best relic sites are found in either nullsec or wormhole space, both of
which are relatively dangerous areas of space but the potential payoff is large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices tip&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Want to try wormhole exploration? See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/reference/wormholes/&#34;&gt;Your First Wormhole&lt;/a&gt;
page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can read more about exploration in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Exploration&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Exploration&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;, and more about wormholes in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Wormholes&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Wormholes&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;.
If exploring in dangerous space, you may also want to read up on how to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Bookmarks#Safe_Spots&#34;&gt;create safespot bookmarks&lt;/a&gt;
and use your &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Directional_Scanner_Guide&#34;&gt;directional scanner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices info&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;You will notice that many exploration guides mention cloaking devices. Alpha
clones aren&amp;rsquo;t able to use cloaking devices, which means you will be a bit more
vulnerable to attack. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to pay attention to your surroundings
to avoid getting ganked while scanning and hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploration can be an excellent source of income, particularly if you&amp;rsquo;re willing
to brave the riskier areas of space such as nullsec and wormhole space. It&amp;rsquo;s also
very good income relative to the amount of training required, as even a new pilot
with basic scanning and hacking skills in a t1 frigate can potentially get the
same loot as a high-skilled pilot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faction Warfare</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/fw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/fw/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faction Warfare involves PvP in the faction-contested lowsec regions. The four
factions gain and lose territory as they fight, and participants earn rewards
based on their efforts to help conquer territory for their faction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If faction warfare PvP sounds interesting to you, read more about it
in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Factional_Warfare&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Faction Warfare&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Factional_Warfare_strategy_and_tactics&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;FW strategy and tactics&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;
guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faction Warfare can be a great way to find semi-structured PvP objectives
with potential rewards. Because faction warfare sites have restrictions on
what classes of ships can enter them, you have the option of fighting with
only smaller classes of ships that are often cheaper to fit - which means
you can fit (and lose) more of them as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faction Warfare rewards involve significant amounts of Loyalty Points (LP)
which can be exchanged for military faction equipment, either to use yourself
or sell on the market for ISK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet PvP</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/fleet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/fleet/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fleet PvP involves flying together with potentially hundreds of other players,
to meet fleets of other players on the field of battle and destroy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most large fleets are driven by battles between corporations.
As such, taking place in a large fleet battle usually means being in one of the corporations involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the better-known corporations which actively recruit new players and
seek out large-scale fleet battles are Brave Newbies and Pandemic Horde.
These battles can also be found in many, many corporations throughout New Eden;
probably the best place to search is in sovereignty-holding nullsec alliances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some groups which accept pilots from any corporation into their fleets,
and then set out to stir up trouble against any groups they come across
(known as &amp;ldquo;NPSI&amp;rdquo; fleets, for &amp;ldquo;Not Purple, Shoot It&amp;rdquo;, referring to the fact that
any non-fleetmate is a viable target)
rather than trying to accomplish a strategic objective for their own benefit.
The best-known of these is Spectre Fleet, but others certainly exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternately, the group Red Vs. Blue holds arranged fleet battle in high-security space,
and focuses on new-player-friendly ships and relatively fair fights,
offering the large fleet battle experience without the commitment of living in null-security space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large fleet battles are primarily driven by conflicts between player corporations and alliances.
Conflicts can arise for a variety of reasons - desire to claim more territory and enjoy its resources,
grudge matches over long-ago insults, mercenary contracts, or any of a countless number of others.
By working together, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the chance to make a lasting mark on the face of EVE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ganking</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/ganking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/ganking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-security space is as close to safe as EVE gets.
However, it&amp;rsquo;s not perfectly safe, and if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to accept the consequences,
you can prey on other players in this &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; space,
destroying their ships for fun and profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high-security space, CONCORD - the spacecops -
will arrive to punish any criminal within seconds after they commit the act.
There is no way to evade CONCORD&amp;rsquo;s retribution; once you fire your weapons illegally,
your ship &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be destroyed moments later.  Additionally, you will take a penalty to your
&amp;ldquo;security status&amp;rdquo; (CONCORD&amp;rsquo;s opinion of you), and if it gets low enough (starting at -2.0),
you will be hunted by faction police when you enter high-security space.
Security status is restored by destroying NPC pirates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, the main art of &amp;ldquo;suicide ganking&amp;rdquo; is finding a way
to ensure your target is destroyed before CONCORD has a chance to arrive,
and to do it economically enough to permit yourself a chance at profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual tools of the ganker are a destroyer, or possibly a cruiser,
fit for the maximum damage output possible in the shortest period of time,
and with the cheapest equipment that allows that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it is common to work with a friend or two:
hang out on major trade routes, with a friend a jump or two ahead using a
&lt;code&gt;Cargo Scanner&lt;/code&gt; on ships to find targets carrying items of value,
then another friend on standby to scoop the items from their wreck
after they (and you) are destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONCORD responds more slowly in systems of lower security status,
and for that reason most suicide ganks are carried out in systems of
0.5 and 0.6 security.  In these systems, the highest raw damage-per-second
is preferable; in very high-security systems, the &amp;ldquo;alpha-strike&amp;rdquo; damage
of a single shot is often more relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ship&amp;rsquo;s safety systems will automatically prevent you from committing an illegal act.
To disable them, click on the colored dot to the upper left of your health/capacitor readout.
&amp;ldquo;Disable Safety&amp;rdquo; will allow you to commit any act, including those that invite CONCORD retribution.
&amp;ldquo;Partial Safety&amp;rdquo; prevents you from doing anything that draws CONCORD&amp;rsquo;s wrath,
but permits you to become a &amp;ldquo;suspect&amp;rdquo; via lesser crimes such as looting another player&amp;rsquo;s wreck,
temporarily allowing other players to shoot you without CONCORD interference but not provoking CONCORD themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some gankers manipulate the criminal justice system in order to destroy their targets &amp;lsquo;legally&amp;rsquo;.
By dropping a cargo container and enticing your target to take it,
you can get them to send themselves Suspect, allowing them to shoot you freely.
Alternately, by deliberately going Suspect around a player who you&amp;rsquo;ve irritated,
you may provoke them to shoot at you - allowing you to shoot them back in self-defense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many players regard high-security space as safe,
and will fly around in very fragile ships
with a great deal of value in their cargo holds.
Relieving them of this undeserved wealth can be a nice way to enrich yourself -
and, if you&amp;rsquo;re so inclined, to harvest some tears as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hauling</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/hauling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/hauling/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hauler&amp;rsquo;s trade involves ferrying goods along the spacelanes of New Eden,
whether raw materials to fuel the fires of industry,
weapons, ammunition and ships to replace the losses of PvPers,
or transporting underpriced goods to a location where they can be sold for a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary tool of a hauler is the Industrial ship.
These ships can haul tens or hundreds of times as much cargo as combat vessels,
while being remarkably cheap themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If looking to be a trucker-for-hire, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to look primarily at Courier contracts.
Other players can offer payment to those willing to relocate their goods,
rather than moving every ship, module and piece of ammo themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When accepting a courier contract, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to provide some ISK as collateral.
That ISK will be returned to you when you complete the contract,
but if you fail to complete it for any reason (such as the loss of your ship and the package),
the collateral will be forfeit.  You can peek inside the packages you&amp;rsquo;re transporting
to see what&amp;rsquo;s inside - if it&amp;rsquo;s worth more than the collateral, you can simply keep the package yourself,
forfeiting the collateral but gaining their goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding a good courier contract can often be tough - there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other haulers out there,
and many of the contracts available at any times are the ones other haulers have already
declined to take, often due to poor rewards for the time and risk investment.
Additionally, some courier contracts are, in essence, traps, requiring you to move through
low-security space where you can be attacked freely, or requiring you to deliver things to a
station where you cannot dock, forcing you to fail the contract and forfeit your collateral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some corporations which have a hauling focus, the most notable being
Red Frog Freight and Push Industries.  Many courier contracts are issued directly
to the hauling corporations rather than through public contracts,
so if space trucking is your thing, you may want to look into joining one of these groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices warning&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;As noted in the Ganking section, other players can attack you in high-security space.
Your best defense against this is to be aware, be alert, and never use autopilot,
as it will leave you vulnerable for long periods while flying to the gates.
Your second-best defense is to carry little enough value in your hold,
and mount strong enough defenses, that you&amp;rsquo;re un-economical to attack.
In an Industrial, a good rule of thumb is not to exceed 20 million ISK in value
for each 10k EHP your ship has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hauling can provide a slow, but steady, stream of income
while requiring a relatively small amount of player attention.
Some also find it soothing to sail amongst the stars
and watch the traffic of other players passing them by.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/mining/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mining involves harvesting resources from asteroids, either in asteroid belts
or special mining signatures located via scanning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to pursue mining as a source of income, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want
to use a Venture, as it is the best dedicated mining ship you have available
as an alpha clone. Its 5000 m^3 Ore Hold allows it to store a significant
amount of ore so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to return to a station to drop off
your ore quite as often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s relatievly easy to sell the ore you mine, though the profits may be relatively
low for highsec miners. Mining in lower security space can increase profits but also
increases the level of risk, as players may frequently try to attack you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about mining in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Mining&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Mining&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mining is probably the most sedate of all EVE income opportunities - once
your mining lasers are activated on an asteroid, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly just waiting
for the raw ore to come streaming in. If you&amp;rsquo;re mostly interested in socializing
with other players, it can be a great activity to do while socializing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Running</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/missions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/missions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission running is PvE content: getting missions from NPC agents
and then completing them for the mission rewards and the bounties from
any hostile NPCs you destroy along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to pursue mission running as a source of income, you&amp;rsquo;ll
want to build up standing with a particular NPC corporation in order
to get access to higher tiers of mission agents (which can then give
you harder missions with better rewards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to tackle these harder missions you&amp;rsquo;ll also want to continue
upgrading to larger classes of ships such as cruisers and battlecruisers.
In general, you&amp;rsquo;ll want:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frigates/destroyers for Level 1 missions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Destroyers/cruisers for Level 2 missions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cruisers/battlecruisers for Level 3 missions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A well-fit battlecruiser for Level 4 missions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;notices note&#34; &gt;&lt;p&gt;The only battlecruiser that alpha clones can use is the &lt;code&gt;Gnosis&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can read more on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Missions&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Missions&amp;rsquo; page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve received a mission from an agent, you can look it up in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eve-survival.org/wikka.php?wakka=MissionReports&#34;&gt;EVE-Survival&lt;/a&gt;
mission listings to get more details about what kind of dps you might face
from enemies in the mission and which enemise may trigger more spawns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mission running produces a fairly steady stream of ISK - the mission rewards
will pay out a certain amount, plus you&amp;rsquo;ll also be paid the bounties for any
hostile NPCs you killed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also be rewarded with loyalty points (LP) for the NPC corporation that
is giving you the missions. These LP can be traded for items from the NPC corp&amp;rsquo;s
Loyalty Point Store.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ratting</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/ratting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/ratting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunting NPC pirates (&amp;ldquo;rats&amp;rdquo;) is PvE content,
searching through space for hostiles and destroying them for bounties and loot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary places rats can be found are in asteroid belts
and in Combat Anomalies.  Combat Signatures can contain
difficult sites full of tough rats as well, but those need
a probe scanner to find, and thus require cooperation with an Explorer
(or a scanning ship of your own).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rats get progressively tougher - and with progressively better bounties -
as you further down the scale of system security.
In most highsec systems, ratting isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly worth bothering with,
while in deep nullsec it can provide tens of millions of ISK per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asteroid belts are usually less lucrative, but (especially in nullsec)
have the chance to spawn special &amp;ldquo;faction&amp;rdquo; or even &amp;ldquo;officer&amp;rdquo; rats,
which drop extremely rare and valuable modules.  The chance is low,
but winning the asteroid-belt lottery can give a nice infusion of cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the dangers from hostile players in nullsec are extreme, taking
full advantage of nullsec ratting will usually require joining
a nullsec corporation, so that you can live in their space unmolested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ratting can be a reliable moderate income stream,
with occasional jackpots of faction modules that can sell
for large sums of ISK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salvaging</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/salvaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/salvaging/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvaging is the practice of using a Salvager module
to harvest wrecks, acquiring Salvage used to build rigs
or be sold on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Salvager and Tractor Beam modules that are the tools of the salvager&amp;rsquo;s trade
require a free highslot.  As such, destroyers, with their copious high slots,
are the typical ships of a salvage pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvaging wrecks, naturally, requires wrecks to salvage.  As such,
it is common to team up with a mission-runner or ratter,
following behind them and cleaning up the wreckage left in their wake.
Alternately, you can search a system&amp;rsquo;s asteroid belts,
or use Combat Probes to scan down a mission-runner
and salvage their wrecks whether they want you to or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tech Two wrecks can provide exceptionally valuable salvage,
but rats that leave such wrecks are very rare;
the primary source of Tech Two salvage is the aftermath of battles between players.
Picking the bones of a PvP battlefield can be extremely lucrative,
but if you&amp;rsquo;re not allied with one of the parties to the battle,
may result in you just adding your own wreck to the pile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salvaging can be a nice income stream with a very low skillpoint requirement,
which does not require putting yourself at substantial risk.
It can also be a nice way to socialize, if cooperating with the person creating the wrecks you salvage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small-Gang PvP</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/small-gang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/small-gang/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small-Gang PvP is the practice of hopping in a ship,
heading out with yourself and a few friends,
and looking for trouble and the elusive &amp;ldquo;good fight&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a ship and get out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making some friends, or joining a corporation (the latter of which often leads to the former),
means you&amp;rsquo;ll have a group of people to go out on PvP &amp;ldquo;roams&amp;rdquo; with,
but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing stopping you from going out on solo roams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One common piece of advice for new players, once they&amp;rsquo;ve gotten their feet under them
and acquired some ISK, is to buy fifty frigates, then go out and lose each and every one -
and to try and learn something from each death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The targets of PvP roams can be varied, but will almost universally involve
leaving high-security space.  Roaming through lowsec or nullsec are the most common,
but wormhole roams are a possibility as well.  Using &lt;a href=evemaps.dotlan.net&gt;Dotlan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s
maps for the area you&amp;rsquo;re flying through, especially the &amp;ldquo;NPC Kills&amp;rdquo; filter,
can help you pick out areas with player activity; a large number of &amp;ldquo;Ship/Pod Kills&amp;rdquo;
may indicate a gatecamp waiting to pick off anyone who comes through, which,
depending on the size of your gang, may be a good or a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In gangs of more than a couple people, it&amp;rsquo;s fairly common to have one player act as the &amp;ldquo;scout&amp;rdquo;,
moving ahead and finding targets of opportunity for the fleet to attack,
or reporting danger that lies in the way.  This role is perfectly suited to Frigate pilots.
Mastering the use of the Directional Scanner can be vital to a scout;
see &lt;a href=http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Directional_Scanner_Guide&gt;Eve University&amp;rsquo;s Directional Scanner
Guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PvP in EVE can generate quite a rush,
and several pilots report cases of &amp;ldquo;the shakes&amp;rdquo; after a close battle.
Working with your friends to outsmart opponents and overpower them,
or simply prey on any hapless victims you find,
can be a good way to socialize with your fleetmates,
grow as a pilot and, quite simply, have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trading</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/trading/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what&#34;&gt;What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy low, sell high. EVE&amp;rsquo;s economy is almost entirely player driven which means
that there are plenty of ways to make money just by playing the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how&#34;&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of trading: station trading and region trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Station trading involves placing buy orders and sell orders in a station to arbitrage the
gap between the current highest buy price and the current lowest sell price: players sell
goods to your buy order, then you list the same goods for a higher price as a sell order.
You pocket the difference between the two prices in return for running the risk that you
might not be able to sell something for as good a price as you bought it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Region trading involves buying goods from a market in one region of the galaxy, then
moving those goods to another region and selling them there. Because buying items from
the market doesn&amp;rsquo;t automatically move them to a player&amp;rsquo;s current station, players will
often pay extra for goods closer to their current location. Prices will also often vary
between market hubs as supply and demand rise and fall between regions. An astute trader
can take advantage of these varying prices to make ISK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about trading in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/Trading&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;Trading&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people really enjoy the careful planning and execution that goes into successful
trading. Traders can also make large amounts of money if they&amp;rsquo;re good at figuring out
trends and staying ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Else?</title>
      <link>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/something-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 18:56:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/new-goals/something-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVE players have historically been quite creative when it comes to player-driven
content - everything from large dramatic diplomatic affairs to galaxy-shaping
wars and scandals to small interactions noticed only by the couple of players
involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/AdfFnTt2UT0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the ideas listed here, there&amp;rsquo;s also others mentioned in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.eveuniversity.org/EVE_Careers_101&#34;&gt;UniWiki &amp;lsquo;EVE Careers 101&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;
article, not to mention countless other possible ways to play.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/images/wtd.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Image too small? Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://iviguera.github.io/alpha-guide/images/wtd.jpg&#34;&gt;full-size version&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your imagination: how will you make your mark on the EVE universe?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>